Chapter 5: How Could This Go Wrong?

Author's Notes: Milo's character sheet for this year is finally finalized. Sorry for the short (and late) chapter; I've had wisdom teeth-related issues and also got distracted by another project. As such, this chapter and the next one will sort of blend together into one slightly-larger-than-normal chapter in a lot of ways.

Today's Character Sheet: myth-weavers com/sheetview php?sheetid=586163

"Why in the Hells is there a Half-Fiend Horse strapped to that carriage?!"

Silence.

"Does it think it can fool us? Is it simply pretending to be a regular horse?"

Silence.

"Maybe it's trying to lure us in, and then... neigh at us. Evilly."

Silence.

"Foolish evil extraplanar equine Erinyes-extraction! For I can see your true form! Fear my arcane mi—"

"Er," Ron interrupted, "Before you get all worked up and turn that carriage into a smoking crater, mate... what horse are we talking about?"

"The one pulling the carriage," Milo said, gesturing at the bony, black, batwing-sporting horselike-creature. "I mean, just look at it. It has fangs, for gods' sakes! That thing is evil incarnate."

"Yeah... about that," Harry said. "There's nothing there."

"Except for the carriage, which, by the way, is horseless," Hermione added helpfully.

Milo gave Harry, Ron, and Hermione a skeptical look that was only matched by the skeptical look that Harry, Ron, and Hermione were giving him.

"You mean you can't see it?" he said. They gave their murmured assents, still giving him the look people reserved for situations like these. "So, the question is: is it a phantasm, or is it selectively invisible?"

"A phantasm?" Ron asked.

"An illusion," Hermione responded.

"More specifically," Milo clarified, "An illusion that only certain individuals can perceive. There's only one way to find out..."

Hermione gave a look of sudden, horrified clarity and whipped her face around to look Milo dead in the eye.

"No!" she cried.

"—Glitterdust!"

o—o—o—o

Snape paced around Dumbledore's office slowly, his face a careful mask. Only one who knew him very well would have been able to tell just how nervous he was.

"Calm down, Severus," Dumbledore said, though in truth, he didn't feel much better. "No situation is without answer. Once, you see, I was asked, given the choice, if I were to be stranded on a desert island with nothing more than a Caucasian leopard and a ball of cotton twine—"

"He will be expecting a reply, Albus," Snape said coolly. "In fact, he will already be questioning the reason for my delay."

Dumbledore sighed.

"It appears, I am afraid, that we have little choice in the matter. You must brew him the potion."

"Need I remind you that there is no surefire method to discover if someone is utilizing Polyjuice?"

"Perhaps. However, in my experience, actors that exceptionally skilled are few and far between. And you are hardly the only person capable of this task that he can call upon. If you refuse, he will simply call upon another."

"But not one so skilled as I." He wasn't boasting; it was simply the truth. Snape was one of the best potion makers in the world; certainly the best in magical Britain. The duration of the effects of the Polyjuice potion increased with the skill of the maker. At maximum potency, he could brew a Polyjuice that lasted a little over twelve hours. He knew he was fighting a losing battle, however. He wasn't even sure why he was fighting it. What did he care about Lucius's plotting?

"You know as well as I that it would be a simple matter for an infiltrator to contrive an excuse to repeatedly drink some innocuous liquid—under the guise of medicine, perhaps, or a favourite tea."

"Very well, Albus," Snape said. "I shall do as you ask—let us both hope that we do not regret it."

"Indeed. Now, if you will excuse me, I have a Sorting Ceremony to attend t—" Dumbledore paused as he heard the characteristic grinding sound of stone-on-stone that signalled the arrival of a visitor. For all the inconvenience of having a secret, password-protected office, it did provide enough warning to fix one's hair and tuck in one's shirt.

The door slammed open, revealing a beleaguered Professor McGonagall.

"Albus," she gasped. "Come quickly!"

"What's happened, Minerva?" Dumbledore said, leaping to his feet. "Have Death Eaters attacked? Is it another goblin uprising? Have the Cannons won a match?"

"No," she said. "It's much worse than that."

"Allow me to hazard a guess," Snape said. "Milo?"

"Milo."

o—o—o—o

"You know, it really could have been worse," Ron said.

"Can't see how," said Harry.

"Well," Ron said, "at least the bloodshed was kept to a minimum."

The wreckage of dozens of carriages lay scattered across the path. One was on fire; Harry couldn't imagine how it had been lit on fire, but it had. A lone wheel rolled past him, down the shallow slope, and into the lake. A pair of colossal tentacles lashed out of the water, and seized it, never to be seen again. Hogwarts students, second-through seventh year, were standing around, shocked. Some were nursing minor injuries.

"Honestly, Milo, I'd thought you'd have remembered what happened at the Potions Incident!" Hermione said testily. "Someone could have been killed! You could still be expelled!"

"I think we're missing the key point," Milo said defensively. "The point is that we all learned a valuable lesson, didn't we?"

"I should hope so," Hermione said.

"It's that when someone claims to see something that nobody else can, you take them seriously. There really was a Half-Fiend Horse." The Glitterdust had shown that; in addition to blinding its unfortunate victims, it also revealed invisible ones.

"Mate, there wasn't anything even half friendly about them," Ron said.

"Half-Fiend, not half-friend," Hermione clarified. "Honestly, they don't even sound similar. How could you possibly confuse the two?"

Ron shrugged. He opened his mouth to defend himself, but then saw something out of the corner of his eye. "Neville!" he gasped.

Milo followed Ron's gaze to see Neville Longbottom trapped beneath the ruins of a carriage. He then broke into a sprint.

"Are you okay?" he gasped. He could just see Neville's round face sticking out from underneath the shattered wreckage.

"Oh, I'm fine," he said. "It's not as bad as it looks. I'm just a little... stuck. Anyone know what caused the thestrals to bolt?"

"Erm..." Milo said awkwardly.

"Thestrals?" Hermione asked curiously.

"Yeah, the things that pull the carriage. You know, the winged horses."

"Hah!" Milo said, pumping his fist into the air.

"Now, I don't mean to be a bother, but could one of you get this carriage off of me before my ribs finally cave?"

"Levitate," Milo cast, and the carriage gently floated up and off of Neville.

"Mister Amestacia-Liadon!" The voice was out of Milo's second- or third-worst nightmares. It was the kind of voice that could cut across any noise—from unruly fifth-graders to the din of battle—and still be perfectly audible. It was the kind of voice that registered less as sound in your ears and more as a chill in your spine.

It was the voice of Professor McGonagall.

And she was angry.

"Explain."

Milo hesitated for a moment while he considered whether or not to use Bluff, before dismissing it as foolhardy. If anyone had whatever the local equivalent of ranks in Sense Motive was, it would be McGonagall.

"I was surprised by what appeared to be a demon horse, ma'am. However, due to reasons unknown, it was invisible to all other observers—except Neville. I targeted it with a non-damaging spell that marks invisible creatures to others in order that one of my comrades may be able to identify it and respond accordingly." Nothing but the truth. "The creature—which I am now told is a thestral—responded aggressively, as did a few others, as you can see."

McGonagall sighed. "Why me? Why is it alwaysme? Ten points from Gryffindor. Next time, find a professor before you leap to conclusions. These animals have been carrying students from the train station to the castle for three centuries without incident. Now, however, it appears we will have to begin counting anew."

Hermione coughed politely. "Erm, excuse me Professor—"

"Yes, what is it, Ms. Granger?"

"Well, seeing as how the sorting hasn't happened, and as such, term hasn't actually started... well, you can't actually take—or give—house points yet."

"Ha. Good point. No points off, then."

"Brilliant!" Ron said, clapping Milo on the back.

"But I'll be letting Hagrid oversee your detention, seeing as how it was his thestrals you disturbed, and his carriages you destroyed."

"Ah, well, better luck next time, then," Ron said consolingly.

McGonagall turned to the crowd of students, many of whom were still filing off the train, staring at the disaster scene in confusion. "I'm sorry to say that due to... technical difficulties, you will all have to proceed to the castle on foot. Prefects, please gather the students of your house, then follow me."

Milo sighed and went to find Percy, wondering what torment Hagrid would have in store for him. He'd only had occasional contact with the groundskeeper, though, as he was a friend of Harry's, maybe he'd go easy on Milo. That said, Milo shuddered as he remembered his last detention with him.

He found Percy in short order. Ron's older brother had a knack for organization, and without even knowing it, the Gryffindors found themselves marching in order of year and height while the Hufflepuffs were still mucking about.

It was only while slogging through the deep mud and constant drizzle up the path to the castle that Milo realized how uncomfortable it was to have wet feet. Somehow, despite having lived in Scotland for the better part of a year (not to mention the exotic locales adventuring had led him to back home), he'd never really noticed it. It was one of the more unpleasant feelings he'd yet faced, and he'd once been swallowed whole by a Tendriculos.

"Prestidigitation," he muttered, cleaning and drying his socks. He briefly calculated the cost of creating magical socks that kept themselves dry, before discarding it as exorbitant. In any case, the local wizards probably have some for sale. They're much bigger on creature comforts than ours.

Eventually, they made their way to the gates. With one look at the faces of the students—and McGonagall—not even the gargoyles that guarded the doors caused any problems. By the time that they finally reached the warmth and comfort of the Great Hall, nearly everyone was soaked, shivering, and sniffling.

Suffice to say that the first years, who had already been enjoying the roaring fire and pumpkin juice, were not popular among the older students just then.

Milo considered himself lucky that only a very, very small number of them knew that he was held responsible—though personally, he felt that it was wildly irresponsible of the school to use demonic monstrosities as a means of transport without giving fair warning first.

"Hey, Nev," Milo said as they sat down at the Gryffindor table. "How come only we could see them?"

"Um..." Neville said slowly. "You have to, um, have seen death."

"What, like, Nerull? No, wait, you lot call him the Reaper. Pretty sure I'd know if I saw him. Unless he was in disguise; Nerull has, like, 29 Charisma and ten levels in Rogue... now there's a thought to keep a person up at night."

"No, as in, you have to see something die."

"Oh." Milo blinked. "Hey, everyone," he said. Harry, Hermione, Ron, and a few other startled Gryffindor NPCs turned to look at him. Milo reached out and slammed his mug down on a passing ant. "You should all thank me. You can see thestrals now."

There was an awkward silence before conversation resumed, and everyone collectively adopted their default 'Respond-To-Milo' protocol; that is, they pretended neither to have seen nor heard him. Milo tended to get that a lot.

"I don't think that's how it works," Neville said. "Pretty sure it has to be, you know, a person." He hesitated for a moment. "I'm sorry. About whoever it was."

"Hm? Oh, don't even worry about it." As an adventurer, Milo had seen dozens of bandits, scores of orcs, and kobolds beyond number meet violent ends. "I guess that'd be proof that You-Know-Who's still around, if we still needed it."

"Oh?"

"Yeah, well, if he really died when he tried to kill Harry as a baby, then Harry would be able to see thestrals."

"What about his, you know..." Neville's voice dropped into a whisper, "...his parents?"

"Well, they didn't necessarily die in line-of-sight of him," Milo responded in a whisper, following Neville's lead. "Could have been in a different room altogether, or he could have been looking the other way."

Neville thought for a moment. "Then he might not have been looking at You-Know-Who either. Maybe he was, I dunno, held up by the scruff of his neck."

"Fair point." Despite Neville's reasoning, Milo felt pretty sure that Voldemort would want to stare into the eyes of his prophesised foe. It was the sort of thing Thamior the Repulsively Repugnant Reprobate would do. Milo found himself wistfully missing his days fighting against the evil Wizard; while dangerous, at least he was straightforward. This world seemed to be full of twists and turns and red herrings and unexpected reveals...

The doors to the Great Hall slammed open.

Milo whipped his head around to see what would, no doubt, be, finally, some clue as to what to expect in this adventure.

Gilderoy Lockhart entered, somehow managing to, despite being soaked and covered in mud, look merely roguishly dishevelled. He was followed by Hagrid, who looked anything but.

"So sorry," Lockhart said, flashing them all a perfect smile, "I was delayed slightly showing old Hagrid here a few tricks for rounding up thestrals—not that he needed it, of course. Don't be getting the idea that, simply because I once taught a Dementor the true meaning of Christmas, I'm in any way better than your stout groundskeeper."

Hagrid's typically-cheerful face resembled a stepped-on cat, but he kept his mouth shut. It took obvious effort.

"I told you Githyanki Lawnart would be our new DADA teacher," Milo said, feeling very smug. It was about time he was right about something.

"Oh, I thought it was obvious from the reading list," said one of the Weasley twins, overhearing him in a lull in conversation.

"That's what I said, George, but this lot—" Milo nodded to Harry and the others, "—said I was being paranoid."

"Fred, actually. And what does Lockhart have to do with being paranoid?"

"Nothing..." Milo drifted off as he was struck by an idea. Everyone was in the Great Hall. "Cover for me, George. Invisibility." Milo always found it disconcerting seeing his hands vanish. Odd, now that he thought about it, that he could still close his eyes to prevent himself from seeing...

"It's Fred!" he protested.

Milo slipped out, deciding to take advantage of having complete run of the castle.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

D&D Tip: You know how Elmer Fudd feels when he's chasing Bugs off a cliff and keeps running for awhile until Bugs hands him a book explaining gravity and he falls? Turns out that's how D&D works, too. Check this out:

Monks are not actually proficient with unarmed strike.

Now that you know, you can't unlearn it.

Happy gaming!

Chapter 7: A Head Full of Hot Heir

Author's Notes: Individual or individuals unknown are using every variant of "SirPoley," "Sir Poley," "Sir_Poley," " ," etc. as an Xbox Live gamer tag. I'm "The Sir Poley" as a result, but I'm not thrilled about it. If you see one of these elusive "Sir Poley" imitators out there on Halo or Call of Duty, show 'em what I think about doppelgangers. Even if they're on your team.

Grumblegrumblegrumble.

"Right," Milo said. He, Harry, Ron, and Hermione had pushed several desks together in an abandoned classroom to form an ad-hoc war room. A few snacks and drinks, liberated from the leftovers of the Sorting Feast, were scattered across the table. "I trust yesterday's incident has put to rest any speculation that this would be an ordinary school year?"

Everyone nodded.

"Excellent. I believe it is time for us to update the Plot." Once again, he had cast Silent Image ahead of time, so it simply appeared with a magic-y looking wave of his hand. "The way I see it, we have a very definite Evil Plot going on right under our noses. I've already taken the liberty of drawing up a list of suspects. There are a limited number of creatures that are capable of causing Petrification—in my world, in any case."

"Petrification?" Harry asked.

"Being frozen," Hermione explained. "All of your muscles lock up and you are put in a comatose state."

"For how long?"

"Permanently. Your body is in complete lockdown, and doesn't age or get hungry or thirsty or anything. With some magical protection against the elements, you could stay that way for centuries. There's only one known cure, and that's a potion made from mandrake roots."

"Which brings me to my second point. Petrification in this world more closely resembles Paralysis or heavy Dexterity drain in my world. Where I'm from, Petrification means getting turned completely to stone. This means that, once again, my knowledge will be partially correct at best. I can't take anything for granted. That's where you come in."

"How so?" Hermione asked.

"I'll list off the most common creatures from my world which can cause Petrification, and you'll tell me what they do here, if they even exist. Of course, none of this is ruling out Dark Magic."

"Fair enough."

"Medusa?"

"She writes an advice column for the Daily Prophet," Ron said. "But she's a witch, not a monster."

"There was also a Gorgon named Medusa," Hermione added. "But that was thousands of years ago. She was said to be the most beautiful woman who ever lived, but, now that I think about it, there are a lot of 'most beautiful women who ever lived' in legends."

"A beautiful Gorgon?" Milo was aghast. "Who could ever find an eight-foot wrought-iron cow beautiful? Except a Rust Monster..."

"No, Gorgons are beautiful women with snakes for hair who can turn anyone who looks at them into stone," Hermione clarified.

"Hold up," Ron said thoughtfully. "If you get turned to stone when you look at them, how does anyone know that they're beautiful?"

"Magic," Hermione shrugged.

"Ugh," Milo said. "This is more complicated than I thought it would be. For some reason, your world calls Medusas Gorgons. What do you call your two-ton, eight-foot wrought-iron cows then? Pixies?"

"Dolores Umbridge," Hermione answered, completely straight-faced.

"Well played. What about Basilisks?"

"What's a Basilisk?" Harry asked.

"A six-legged giant lizard thing that turns you to stone."

"We haven't got any of those, either," Hermione said.

"Anything else you have that Petrifies people?"

"Nothing I can name off the top of my head," Hermione said. "But I'll have to do more research to say for sure."

"What can you tell me about the Chamber of Secrets, then?"

"Not a lot. It's briefly mentioned in Hogwarts: A History, though—but I thought you would know that, seeing as how you've read every book in the library?"

"Still working my way through the Q's, actually," Milo said defensively. "You'd be surprised how prolific a writer Quinta Quirinia Quirrellia was, and reading with Comprehend Languages is such a pain. I had no idea that it didn't translate idioms—turns out everyone in my world uses the same ones. Incidentally, I think Quirrell might be the last scion to an ancient noble family. Who knew? In any case, I read it before I had ranks in Autohypnosis."

"Whatever happened to Quirrell, anyway?" Harry asked.

"Still in St. Mungo's," Ron answered. "Apparently he's in some sort of coma."

"Shame," Harry said. "I bet he knows all about whatever Voldemort's planning. Where were we?"

"Chamber of Secrets," Hermione replied. "Apparently there was some disagreement between the four founders about what kind of students should be allowed to attend Hogwarts. Salazar Slytherin believed that only purebloods should be allowed to attend their school—"

"He would," Ron muttered.

"—and he got into an argument with Godric Gryffindor about it. It ended with Salazar leaving Hogwarts—"

"Probably through the Astronomy Tower window," Ron snickered.

"—never to return. Legend has it that Slytherin built a secret room somewhere in the castle with a horror trapped inside that could only be opened by his heir." Hermione paused.

"Is that it?" Milo asked.

"No," she said. "I was just waiting to see if Ron had any more delightful commentary."

"Actually," Ron said. "I was working on something brilliant involving Slytherins all being full of hot heir. Pure gold, eh?"

"Probably one of your best yet," Hermione said.

"Thanks!" Ron beamed.

"That wasn't a compliment. Anyway, the horror is supposed to purge Hogwarts of those Salazar Slytherin doesn't deem... fit to learn."

"Hmm," Milo said. "Well, that confirms that Slytherin House has been evil right from the start, which, admittedly, is hardly a surprise. It also explains why the Chamber went after Peeves."

"Oh?"

"Could you imagine anything less worthy in someone like Salazar Slytherin's eyes than a creature that exists only to give people wedgies?"

"The Chamber could also be a distraction," Harry noted.

"Yeah," agreed Ron. "Someone found something that could finally get Peeves what he deserved, and, in order to avoid getting caught—not that anyone would try too hard to find him, mind—he says the Chamber of Secrets did it."

"Which brings up another question," Harry added. "What could a secret room possibly do to someone?"

"Clearly, Petrify them," Milo said. "You saw Peeves. Maybe it's Animated? Though it'd be a bit conspicuous if a big old ancient mysterious room was seen slinking down the second floor hallway after lunch. Maybe if it had a cunning disguise... a hat and false mustache, perhaps..."

"No, no," Hermione said. "It's a monster. There's a monster in the Chamber."

"Oh, well, obviously," Milo said quickly. "I certainly never seriously entertained the notion that the Chamber tried to disguise itself as a student. Besides, how could a room buy a false mustache? Hah hah, heh heh, hah..."

Everyone stared at him for a long moment.

"Anyway. It's all just rumour, in any case," Hermione reminded them. "There have been countless thorough searches over the centuries for it, none of which had any success."

"Yeah," Ron said. "But... here's the thing. If it was just a rumour, right, why would there be, you know, countless thorough searches?"

"Sorry?"

"I mean, wouldn't, you know, some Headmaster who was a little, well, weird go look for it once or twice, but... if nobody thought it was real, why did so many people look?"

"Maybe for the same reason Muggles look for Bigfoot in North America?" Hermione suggested.

"They're still wasting their time looking for Bigfoot?" Ron snorted. "Hah! Muggles.

"Well, most of them don't really think they'll find him. I think it's more of an excuse to go out camping."

"I should say they wouldn't," Ron said, still laughing. "He works for the Ministry."

Harry nearly choked on his pumpkin juice.

"Well, yes, anyways," Milo said, desperately trying to keep the conversation on topic. "Thank you, Hermione, for that wonderful bit of exposition."

"You're welcome," Hermione said happily. "Would you believe I almost left my copy of Hogwarts: A History at home?"

"Honestly?" Milo said, "No. So it's definitely a monster then?"

"Or a decoy," Harry added.

"Right. A monster or a decoy. Now, how do we figure out which is which?"

"A stakeout?" Ron suggested. "I'm sure if we asked, we'd find loads of volunteers willing to keep sentry duty. We are in the house of courage."

"Great idea, except that pretty much every monster Milo and Hermione mentioned Petrifies when you see it," Harry countered. "So all we'd be doing is giving it easy access to victims."

"So we'll ask first-years to do it," Ron shrugged.

"Ron!" Hermione said, aghast. "We do not use first-years as bait!"

"Calm down, Hermione, I meant Slytherin first-years. We could disguise ourselves as Slytherins, follow them to their Common Room—which would be useful for pranking purposes in the future in any case—and tell them that, in the name of Slytherin, they have to track down this monster in order to, I dunno, help it or something."

"Perfect!" Milo said. "And then all we have to do is follow the trail of Petrified Slytherins to its lair!"

"If we're lucky," Harry said dreamily, "it'll make an exception and eat Malfoy."

"No," Hermione said sharply.

"But—"

"Just no."

"Fine, then," Milo said. "What do you suggest we do?"

"We let Professor Dumbledore, the most powerful wizard of his generation, handle it. If we discover any information, we give it to him or Professor McGonagall."

"How does that result in Malfoy being eaten?" Ron asked.

Hermione sighed.

"Here's an idea," Milo said slowly. He could practically feel the gears whirring in his mind, like the Clockwork Nirvana of Mechanus. "The Chamber can only be opened by the heir of Slytherin, right?"

"According to what I feel I must remind you is legend," Hermione said.

"Pft. When have you ever heard of a legend that wasn't true? Case in point: Bigfoot." Hermione muttered something under her breath, but it seemed somehow insincere to Milo. He began to wonder if she wasn't simply playing Pit Fiend's Advocate because she felt expected to. "So, under the assumption that the legend is true, only the heir of Slytherin can open the Chamber of Secrets and unleash the monster living inside. Correct?"

"Correct."

"It's probably also safe to assume that there isn't an heir of Slytherin just kicking around in Hogwarts, not opening the Chamber of Secrets. Also correct?"

"Reasonable enough," Hermione said. "It would seem fairly improbable. Although, if you consider how many descendents he could have had in a thousand years and compare it to how many pureblooded wizards there really are in Magical Britain, it's entirely possible that Ron here is the heir of Slytherin—or at least, one of several thousand. Unless they mean his literal heir, in which case, I'll have to do more research, but I'm pretty sure hereditary in that medieval England was by-and-large primogeniture, which narrows it down to non-muggleborn males."

"Don't you mean pureblooded?" Harry asked.

"No, I realized while speaking that not all of Slytherin's descendents over the centuries necessarily shared his prejudices."

"Could have been a muggleborn," Ron said, "if some Slytherin down the line had a squib for a daughter and that squib married a muggle bloke, had all-muggle kids, and a few generations later, one of them had a muggleborn wizard for a son."

"It gets worse," Harry said. "We don't know it doesn't refer to his, you know, legal heir. If one of Slytherin's heirs left everything he had—including the ability to open the Chamber—to someone he wasn't related to by blood, like say someone he adopted..."

"So basically," Hermione said, "it could be anyone at all. Well, except Milo. He's from another universe."

"So we've got nothing?" Harry asked.

"No," Milo said. "We've got something. I can cast a spell called Scrying that will let me spy on someone that I have at least secondhand knowledge of. I don't need to know their name. Normally this is useful to find out what that person is up to, but, in this case, I can just target the 'heir of Slytherin' and see what he—or she—looks like."

"Well," Ron said. "If you could do that, why didn't you already?"

"Well, it takes an hour," Milo said, "and it's not guaranteed to work. Also, I need a big expensive mirror."

"How expensive?" Harry asked.

"A thousand gold pieces—or, via salt, thirty-seven galleons, seven sickles, and eighteen knuts."

Harry made a dismissive noise and shrugged. "I thought this was supposed to be a problem."

Milo grinned. At the rate they were going, they'd have this adventure completed in a week.

o—o—o—o

Peasegood sighed upon entering his office, staring at the mountain of reports on his desk. The funny thing about his desk was that, while the hardwood surface was always covered in urgent reports, empty coffee mugs, quills, and, in general, looked as if it was used as frequently as the head of any understaffed government organization's desk the world over, every single piece of parchment was oriented upside-down—facing the door instead of the chair. The chair, in fact, was pristine. Its leather surface shone in a cheaply expensive way that only a brand-new faux-ancient leather office chair could. Peasegood had never sat in that chair since he'd inherited the post after his predecessor snapped from the pressure. In fact, as far as he knew, nobody had ever sat in that chair. It was even possible that it really was an eighty-year-old leather chair in mint condition rather than the fake most people assumed it was.

Peasegood set down his most recent empty mug on top of the others, adding to a precarious pyramid nearly as high he as he was, grabbed the top stack of urgent reports, and left his office the way he'd come in. A trail of sorts had been worn down the centre of the carpet up to the desk and back to the door; the rest was covered in a thin layer of dust.

"Let's see," he said to himself, flipping through the thick stack of parchment. "A 'muggle with a red hat' saw the Abbots Apparating to their friend's home up in Rutland... Pixies loose in Cardiff... Ugh. Another one from Mad-Eye." He'd been pestering them to do everyone on the top 100 bestsellers in fantasy ever since the Fiction Crisis of 1990, when one of them somehow figured out about Hogwarts. He said it was the only way to be sure.

Behind him, Peasegood heard the characteristic pop! of a Disapparating wizard. Peasegood turned around to see Milton standing in the hallway, his robes tattered and soaked through. There was a time when Peasegood would have asked what happened, but that time had passed.

"Take these ones," Peasegood said, shoving half the stack into Milton's hands. "I'll do the rest."

Milton sighed wearily and looked at the reports. "A muggle policewoman reverted?" he asked, looking at the one from Miss Figg. "I hate having to do the same job twice. Ah, well. An Obliviator's work is never done." With another pop, he vanished.

o—o—o—o

Lockhart lounged in a comfortable armchair in the Headmaster's office. The Headmaster had assembled the four Heads of Houses and himself to his office. He didn't actually feel comfortable—to the contrary, he was decidedly anxious—but he'd been in the business long enough to know how to fake it.

"The question remains," McGonagall said, "was this some variety of hoax, or is it real?"

"Perhaps it is neither," Flitwick added. "It could be an attack by Dark Wizards."

"In some ways it makes no difference," Snape said. "If we are not careful, they could close the school."

"You can't be serious," Lockhart said. "This is the oldest wizarding school in the world. They wouldn't close it over a poltergeist."

"Hogwarts... does not always get the best PR," Flitwick said diplomatically.

"It's The Prophet," McGonagall said contemptuously. "They've had it out for the Headmaster since day one."

"Have they?" Dumbledore asked, for all the world sounding like someone who had been told the governments of the world had been overthrown by ants. "But I was at their first public appearance. It was, as I recall, in a diner that made what were, perhaps, the most memorable banana pancakes of my career—you wouldn't believe what they tried to pass off as maple syrup. But I rather thought they took a shine to me when I gave their saxophonist a few pointers and he said to me, 'Albus, baby, you're one hep cat with supermurgitroid chops and zoot threads. Boys, I think we've got ourselves a hot plate in the mix.' Though I never was quite certain what he meant. Ah, well, I suppose one never can win them all..."

McGonagall coughed pointedly. "No, The Daily Prophet."

"Not the Louisiana-based Rhythm and Blues group?"

"No, the newspaper."

"Why, that rag's had it in for me since day one."

"Well, if it's The Prophet that's your problem," Lockhart said, seizing his opportunity. "I might be able to help you out a bit there. You see, there's a lovely young witch I happen to be acquainted with who writes for that particular reporting establishment. If we act quickly enough, we might be able to... present this issue in a rather different light." Lockhart knew that a legitimate success here, mixed with his numerous false ones, would reinforce his position of being one of the group, something which he saw no reason not to do.

Dumbledore frowned for a moment, thinking. "Very well," he said finally. "But on the condition that the article is, in fact, true. I will not have lies spread to the public on my behalf."

"Why, of course," Lockhart said. "I wouldn't dream of having it any other way."

"The larger matter, of course, is how we will deal with this issue—not how it appears to the wider world," Dumbledore said. "I would gladly give my reputation and position to protect the students of Hogwarts, or, indeed, most any other. So. We must discover if, in fact, this is a hoax, an attack, or legitimate, and then proceed to take proper action. I want everyone to keep their ears, eyes, and noses to the ground, peeled, and unstuffed, respectively. Until we have more information, I fear, our other options are limited. However, it is critical that we all do our best to prevent panic from breaking out among the students. In addition to stamping out rumours as they are found, I want the student clubs and organizations in full swing as quickly as possible—including, of course, Quidditch. Which reminds me; Gilderoy, your... predecessor began a Duelling Club last year that, due to his health concerns, was cancelled abruptly. Would you—if you have the time, of course—be so good as to continue where he left off?"

"Would you believe I was just about to suggest that very same idea?" Lockhart said. Truth be told, he had been meaning to start a Duelling Club. "Teaching the students to defend themselves is of upmost importance, especially considering recent events." It was also just the sort of thing that a legendary hero would do.

"Very well," Dumbledore said. "And that, I believe concludes this week's staff meeting."

o—o—o—o

"I still think Hagrid would win," Seamus Finnigan protested.

"Not a chance," Dean Thomas insisted. "But it's a fight I'd love to see." The two were walking by Hagrid's hut in the middle of an animated argument over the ins-and-outs of giant-on-giant combat.

"I dunno. Has it got any sports in it?"

"Are you kidding? Fencing, fighting, torture, revenge, giants, monsters, chases, escapes, true love, miracles..."

Seamus looked about to respond, but was interrupted by a shrill scream from the forest. The two blinked and hesitated for only a moment before their inner-Gryffindors took over. Wands out, they bravely entered the forest to see if anyone was in need of their help.

o—o

A few minutes later, Hagrid—who had heard the scream, too, but had to finish feeding the still-jumpy thestrals (it was not considered wise to leave thestrals half-fed)—arrived to investigate, crossbow in hand and Fang in tow.

"Show yerself," he called into the forest.

"Just us," Seamus called back. "We heard the scream, too, but didn't find anyone out here."

"Yeh alright?"

"Yup," Dean said.

"Glad ter hear it, but that was ruddy dangerous. Head back ter the castle sharpish; I'll look abou' just ter be sure."

The two Gryffindors nodded and hurried up to Hogwarts. Students these days, Hagrid thought to himself. No sense whatsoever. At least they're alright...

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

D&D Tip: Launch Bolt (SpC 130) is 0th-level Sorc/Wiz spell that fires a bolt as if it had been launched from a light crossbow. Simple enough, right? Maybe useful in an emergency, but even then, what are the odds you have bolts and this spell prepared but no crossbow? However, the spell has hidden uses. The bolt can be substituted for a larger bolt—say a Gargantuan (8sp each, 4d6 damage) or Colossal one (16sp each, 6d6 damage) to create an ad hoc siege engine, albeit one with only an 80 ft range increment. Your DM would be well within his rights to disallow this particular trick, as always, though it's somewhat balanced by the need to carry a wagonload of siege ammo around with you.

Enter Eschew Materials. The bolt fired is a Material Component of the spell, and as such is unneeded with the feat. Even without the above trick, this makes Launch Bolt the most damaging cantrip I've found at 1d8 (not exactly an impressive achievement, to be fair), but combined with the above trick, it becomes pretty much insane at low levels. Eschew Materials lets you ignore any material component worth 1gp or less, so the biggest you can fire is Gargantuan (8sp). But don't let that limit your creativity. The bolt can have any special properties you can come up with, as long as it's worth equal to or less than 1gp. That includes special materials (though you're barred from most Core materials, as even silver costs +2gp. So you pretty much only get Cold Iron).

Happy gaming!

EDIT: The Pratchett reference was not supposed to be about his Alzheimer's at all, but the fact that it is occasionally suggested that Discworld's Unseen University is based off of Hogwarts, despite appearing in Discworld books several years before Harry Potter was published. The joke I was making was that Pratchett really did discover the "real" Hogwarts and base the UU off of it, but that his memory was modified afterward. The connection to his disease, however, never crossed my mind. Now that it's been pointed out, I realize that the joke was in poor taste, and removed it. I'm so sorry about that.

Chapter 13: Conspirators

Sunday mornings, unsurprisingly, were not a traditionally busy time for the Hog's Head Inn. Most of its clientele tended to be too busy sleeping off Saturday evening to do much more than (at best) order kippers, eggs, and prodigious amounts of coffee, pepper-up potion, and the establishment's signature hangover cure (coffee mixed with pepper-up potion).

This Sunday morning was something of an eccentric iconoclast in the world of Sunday mornings. Much to the irritation of those upstairs, the Hog's Head was packed with housecoat-wearing, Daily Prophet-clutching, astonished, and, above all, talkative early risers, several of whom would be going home that day to their families, hexed for seven generations to have jaws that clicked by an irritated hag attempting to sleep in a room directly over the bar.

These people were the worst sort of people that could be found in all the world: morning people. Today, they inflicted themselves upon humanity by asking each other inane questions to which they already knew the answer.

"Did you see the paper?" one asked to a table of people, most of whom were holding said paper.

"Have you heard?" asked another.

"It must be some sort of error," said a third stubbornly, "like when Skeeter ran that hatchet job on him in September."

"You mean when, the next day, she issued a retraction saying that he was a wise, wonderful man who was simply sometimes misunderstood and would have the entire situation under control with help from the most talented wizards and witches the world had ever seen?" asked a fourth.

"Yes," said the third. "That time."

"That always struck me as a bit fishy," said the fourth. "First time she's ever written anything nice about anyone."

"My friend Agnes said her cousin Mable saw Rita Skeeter talking with Gilderoy Lockhart," said a fifth. "In this very room!"

During a lengthy tangent in which the party attempted to locate the seat that Lockhart had been sitting in (for 'historical purposes') and discussed putting up a poster, or, perhaps, a plaque above the door ('sitting-place of Gilderoy Lockhart the Great'), the doors slammed open, causing windows across the building to rattle noisily in their panes.

"Did you hear?" cried the slippers-and-housecoat-clad young man. "Dumbledore's been sacked!"

"No," grumbled the barkeep for the thirteenth time that morning, wiping a dirty mug with an even dirtier cloth. "No, I haven't been. I'm self-employed. Entrepreneurial-like. Can't be sacked."

"Not you, Aberforth," snapped the recent entrant, his jaws clicking annoyingly. "The other Dumbledore."

"Oh, him," Aberforth said, as if he could barely remember the existence of the Dumbledore in question. "Yeah. Yeah, I heard." Then, after a lengthy silence, he added, "Shame."

o—o—o—o

"Everything made ready?" Inspector Hannigan asked. Fiona and Evan nodded. "Doors locked?"

"Yes, sir," Fiona replied.

"Blinds drawn?"

"Yes, sir."

"Swept for bugs?"

"Yes, sir. Both insect and electronic."

"Hmmm," Hannigan frowned. "What about arachnids?" Fiona hesitated. "A joke. It was a joke." The three were meeting in a rarely-used subbasement under the old station. Nobody was quite certain what its purpose was, though a decrepit old chair lying in the corner and some suspicious stains suggested a rather nefarious history sometime in the city's past. Most people generally avoided it because of the damp and the rats, though it had become the home of a few large cardboard boxes full of paperwork. Fiona's partner, Evan Travis, had grudgingly spent all morning assembling a cheap table and a few chairs from IKEA. This had gone relatively successfully, which was to say, one of the chairs had (somehow) been assembled inside-out and the table was precariously slanted. "So," Hannigan said, leaning forward, "what have we got?"

"As far as we can tell," Fiona began, "everything that's happened so far started with an encounter at Number 4, Privet Drive, the residence of one Vernon and Petunia Dursley, as well as their son Dudley." As she mentioned each name, she pulled a full-sized photograph of each individual from a manila envelope and placed them on the pine-veneer table surface. Dudley's had been appropriated from his school, but the pictures of Vernon and Petunia had been taken with a telephoto lens from afar. "As near as we can tell, there is absolutely nothing out of the ordinary on any of these individuals. Vernon is employed as a director at a firm by the name of Grunnings, which makes drills—"

"Ruddy useless drills," Travis muttered. He'd given up trying to make the predrilled dowel holes line up and had tried to make his own. The drill—one of Grunnings' latest models—had sawn five centimetres of table leg clean off when it kicked violently in the process.

"Petunia seems to be a stay-at-home mother, while Dudley attends a private school named Smeltings. Everything seems ordinary—except that the Dursleys are not the only residents of Number 4, Privet Drive." Fiona placed a fourth photograph on the table, this one of a young boy with messy brown hair, brilliant green eyes, and a distinctive lightning scar on his forehead. Fiona nodded to Travis, who had handled this part of the investigation.

"Well, sir," Travis said nervously. He didn't often speak with the inspector personally. "They appear to have one Harry Potter under their protection, apparently their nephew. There's, well, there's not much on him on file. Anywhere. I had to really dig to find any information at all. Seems he attended a series of private and public schools until last year, when, near as we can tell, he disappeared completely."

"What do you mean, 'disappeared'?" Hannigan asked.

"He was to attend Stonewall High, but at the last minute before start of term, the Dursleys called and informed the principal there that Harry would instead be attending a St. Brutus's Secure Centre for Incurably Criminal Boys."

"Harry a delinquent, then?" Hannigan asked. "Doesn't look much like one."

"No, here's the thing," Travis said. "There is no St. Brutus's Secure Centre for Incurably Criminal Boys. There isn't even a saint named Brutus. I checked with a priest to make sure."

"So," Hannigan asked. "What happened to the boy?"

"Well, that's the question," Travis said. "Most of the neighbours say they've never seen nor heard of him, and the Dursleys have never said they had another child living there. One said she'd seen him on occasion, and assumed he was a friend of Dudley's from school. Near as I can tell, the Dursleys have been actively hiding his existence. He's not been seen since."

"Why hasn't Social Services, the Child Protection Unit, or the NSPCC looked into this?" Hannigan asked.

"Maybe they did," Fiona said. "But were made to forget."

"I had PC O'Hara call Social Services," Travis said. "I didn't tell him why, don't worry. They say they have no record of him whatsoever."

"Do we know who his parents are?" Hannigan asked. "Or were, for that matter."

Travis nodded to Fiona, who stood up.

"This is a bit tenuous," she admitted. "Seeing as we couldn't find a birth certificate on Harry anywhere. However... well. Lily Evans. Sister of Petunia Dursley. Born 1960, last seen in 1981. She's Petunia's only sibling, and we're fairly certain none of Vernon's had any children. So if Harry really is their nephew, she is likely to be the mother. We don't know who the father was, and we don't know where the name 'Potter' came from."

"It rings a bell, somehow. 1981..." he said thoughtfully. "Hmm. Anyway. Normally, here, I'd bring the Dursleys in on suspicion of child abuse and possible homicide," Hannigan said, "but I suppose we can't do that, can we?"

Fiona shook her head. "They're being watched closely. Both times that I've had my memory altered—that I'm aware of—occurred after visiting their home."

"Could one of them be our perp, then?" Hannigan asked.

"Could be," Fiona said skeptically. "But based on the report I wrote of the initial attack on the Dursleys' home, it seemed like the, well, the magic was being performed by an unknown third youth, and three accomplices, against the Dursleys."

"I don't suppose we have a name or photograph on any of them?"

"If we had any record, it's been removed."

"So what have we got?"

"A name, a year, a distinctive scar," Fiona said, "and, best of all, a predictable perp."

"1981..." Hannigan said again. "That was a bad year to be a copper. Before your time, of course. Homicides and strange disappearances had been on the rise for years, but they were at their worst then. I was just a constable then, and it seemed like every week I was trying to find some new missing person. People were afraid to go outside in broad daylight, and they blamed us. Said it was our job to protect them. Well, it was, I suppose, but what could we do? Then it ended, as suddenly as it began." Hannigan frowned. "Hallowe'en," he said finally. "God. I haven't thought about this in years. No; not Hallowe'en. It was a day or two after. There was some kind of convention of weirdos in town. Wearing robes, if you could believe it. Well, half the force was sent out; we thought they were partygoers who hadn't quite realized that Hallowe'en had ended the night before and the time for fancy dress was over. They were scaring people. They don't much like weirdos up in Little Whinging; not like in London."

"Er, sir..." Fiona said.

"I'm getting to the point, Sergeant. When I said they ought to go back home, they said, they said 'it's Harry Potter Day and even a mugger like you ought to be celebrating.' A mugger! It was as if they'd never seen the uniform before."

"Harry Potter Day?" Travis asked. "Never heard of it."

"Doesn't exist," Hannigan said. "I researched it. Mind, Harry Potter is a common name. And I could be remembering wrong. Memory. Can't always trust it, especially lately. Still, if you had a group of, what, magicians or something, what would you expect them to wear? Cloaks and robes. Merlin-style."

"What," Travis said skeptically, "they just wake up, grab their pointy hats and magic staves, tuck their beards into their belts and walk down the street as if they were taking a stroll to Bag-End? I think someone might have noticed that by now."

"They were pretty sloshed," Hannigan shrugged. "And besides, it might be completely unrelated."

"Also, the popular image of a magician wearing robes and pointy hats has to have come from somewhere, doesn't it?" Fiona said. "So, sir. What do we do?"

"Right. Travis, report Harry Potter as missing to the Child Protection Unit. They can investigate that angle for us. Who knows, if they put his face on the telly, someone might recognize him. Also, the Dursleys might crack if they come knocking on their door. Could lead us somewhere."

"But, if my name is on the report," Travis protested, "they might hunt me down. I don't want to forget again."

"Good point. Submit it under the name 'L'Angelo Misterioso.'"

"L'Angelo Misterioso?"

"DI Parsons down there and us in investigations have an understanding of sorts," Hannigan said. "Sometimes we encounter, well, situations up their alley," he explained. "But for one reason or another our evidence is inadmissible, usually because our paperwork isn't in order—"

"You mean when you don't have a warrant?" Fiona asked, clearly trying, and failing, to mask disapproval.

"Yes. Such as, for example, right now. Parsons will know to investigate without looking too closely at who tipped them off. I don't care if the boy was disappeared by magic or used magic to disappear. There's fifty-seven million people living in the United Kingdom, and someone will have seen something."

"Will do, sir," Travis said snappily.

"Now, Fiona," Hannigan said. "I want you to keep looking for the boy's parents. My gut says there's something significant about 1981. What happened to Lily Evans? Who was the father? Did they ever marry? Did she ever have a job? Friends? Where did she go to school? Find someone who knew her and you'll find her."

"Very well, sir. And if I may ask, what will you be doing?"

Hannigan smiled. "I have a lot of friends who are still very, very sore about what happened twelve years ago. We need allies. With only the three of us, we're in a very precarious position. If our perp figures out what we're up to, we could be made to forget—or simply removed altogether, and their problems would be solved. Nobody would know what to look for, or even to look. What we need is a conspiracy. Someone to check up on us, remind us what's happening if we forget. People with access to more and different information than us."

o—o—o—o

Professor McGonagall paced back and forth in Dumbledore's—in her office. She couldn't believe the situation had spun out of control so fast. One minute she was enjoying a cool glass of pumpkin juice and reading the paper, and the next, a horrified Lavender Brown ran into her office to say that half the Slytherin Quidditch team had been Petrified, and their ears turned into cumquats. They never did find out what had happened to their ears, but it was quite clear what had Petrified them: Slytherin's monster. And she'd only just begun to organize an effort to move them to the hospital wing when a half-crazed Lavender Brown, who McGonagall had just sent back to her Common Room, pushed her way through the crowd to say that Milo Amastacia-Liadon had gone mad and destroyed Gryffindor Tower. Halfway up to the tower, she'd been assaulted by a very persistent owl from the Ministry carrying a letter that said she had to appear before the Wizengamot immediately.

It was there that she had been told that the Hogwarts' Board of Directors had spoken unanimously. Dumbledore was to be removed from his position as Headmaster immediately, and was to have no further contact with any students of Hogwarts, present or future. He was to take full responsibility for the Petrifications. McGonagall was instated as Headmistress, and told that if she didn't end the 'spree' of attacks, she would go the same route as Dumbledore had.

There was a knock at the door.

"Enter," McGonagall called, sitting uncomfortably in Dumbledore's favourite chintz armchair.

Snape, Flitwick, and Sprout entered.

"You sent for us, Minerva?" Flitwick said.

"I'm sure you've all heard what happened," McGonagall said. "I believe we should come up with a plan to deal with the current crisis."

"Are you referring to my Petrified students?" Snape asked angrily. McGonagall often forgot that, despite his cool exterior, he could be fiercely protective of his Slytherins. "Or the sudden removal of the Headmaster?"

"Or the incident up in Gryffindor Tower?" Sprout asked.

"All of those," McGonagall said.

"What about the missing students?" asked Flitwick.

McGonagall frowned. "You mean missing student, surely?" she said. "We will make every effort to locate Dean Thomas."

"Nobody has seen nor heard from Penelope Clearwater, Luna Lovegood, or Anthony Goldstein since last evening," Flitwick said gravely. "I've spent the last nine and a half hours searching for them. I had assumed that was to be the purpose of this meeting."

"Merlin!" McGonagall said. "We'll organize a search party. Don't worry, Filius, we'll find your missing Ravenclaws."

"Not only Ravenclaws," Sprout said. "Susan Bones, Zacharias Smith, and Justin Finch-Fletchley haven't been seen since dinnertime."

McGonagall stared at her. She felt her jaw moving, but couldn't quite make words form. Seven missing students? She hadn't imagined her first day as Headmistress to be going quite like this.

"Well," Snape said. "Things do seem to be falling apart."

That was it. McGonagall felt something click inside of her, and, suddenly, she was giving orders faster than she could think.

"It's Sunday," McGonagall said. "So none of us have to worry about teaching today. I want every student to stay in their Common Rooms for the time being. Pomona, you're going to head the search party. Grab Lockhart, even if you have to drag him out of his office by the scruff of his neck. Filius, contact the Ministry. Amelia Bones at the DMLE is going to move heaven and earth to find her niece if it turns out she's not on the grounds, and she'll likely be with the rest. Severus, about the supposed Chamber of Secrets—"

"Believe me," Snape said. "I've looked. It won't do any good; only the Heir can find it. Unless you happen to have an Heir of Slytherin hiding in your pocket?"

"I know that!" McGonagall snapped. "We've all looked for it one time or another. Forget the Chamber and worry about the monster, Severus. You know more about the Dark Arts, including its dark creatures, than any of us here, and you know it. Find out what's hurting our students and how we can kill it."

Snape looked at her for a short moment, then nodded. "Very well," he said. There was a hint of approval in his voice.

"Also, for the time being, you're Deputy Headmaster," McGonagall said. "I know it's what Albus would have done. Hopefully we can have him back in charge before long, but if we can't... well." McGonagall sighed. "Pomona, how long before we can get those Mandrakes ready?"

"It won't be before early June," she said. "At best."

"Can't we get some sooner than that?"

"Mandrakes must be fully grown for maximum potency," Sprout said. "This is a labour-intensive process that takes the better part of a year. Mandrakes themselves are extremely rare and, due to their potentially fatal cry, heavily restricted by most governments. Their growth requires supervision from highly-trained professionals, but they are required for literally hundreds of different common remedies and cures. You would know better than any, Minerva, that there are always new and exciting transfiguration accidents that require undoing. In short, there is an exceptionally long wait list."

"But surely, for a condition as serious as Petrification, something can be done?" McGonagall asked.

"That's exactly the problem," Sprout said. "If someone's teeth are turned to ice, they need treatment now. But Petrifications... well..."

"Petrified witches and wizards will keep," Snape said. "In fact, they are famous for it. They require no food, no hydration, and they do not age. They will, quite simply, not notice the delay one way or another."

"The average wait for a Petrified witch or wizard is fifty-six years," Sprout said. "Growing them on-site is our only option."

"Very well," McGonagall said. "Well, we have our jobs. Let's get to them. Can you send in the next one on your way out?"

o—o—o—o

"You. In." Snape said to Milo curtly as he walked out of the out of the Headmaster's office, Sprout and Flitwick trailing behind him.

Milo swallowed, then walked up the spiral staircase. The door was open; McGonagall was sitting behind Dumbledore's desk.

"So, they really fired him, then?" Milo asked.

"Unfortunately," McGonagall said. "Now, sit." Without waiting for him to comply, she continued. "Explain yourself. What happened in Gryffindor tower last evening, what is that amber field, and who is inside it disguised as Seamus Finnigan?"

"How could you tell it wasn't Seamus?"

"I'm the Transfigurations Professor. Also, he's holding the wrong wand. It's not even one of Ollivander's."

"I was attacked, the field is caused by magic and is entirely harmless, and it's a Death Eater inside. "

McGonagall stared at him straight in the eye, an unreadable expression on her face. Milo began preparing arguments, counter-arguments, theories, and evidence to back up his accusation to combat her inevitable skepticism.

"Merlin. That explains everything. This certainly has the hallmarks of their interference. Presumably your spell prolongs the effects of Polyjuice, or he would have reverted. You'll have to tell me where you learned to do that." She frowned, deep in thought. "Seamus Finnigan and Dean Thomas are rarely apart, and if Dean is missing... ah. I'll have to tell them to call off the search; the missing students are in the hands of the Death Eaters. But how? Under our very noses?"

Milo could practically hear the wheels of his brain screeching in protest as he forced them to change direction.

"They could have been lured off the grounds and grabbed," Milo reasoned. "Or simply Stunned—or killed—on the grounds near the forest, then carried out. Hogwarts' defences are somewhat... specific. No Apparating or Disapparating on the grounds, but you can show up near them and walk the rest of the way. That's how they grabbed me, last year."

McGonagall's face betrayed a flicker of surprise. Milo wasn't certain how much Dumbledore had told her about the events of last year.

"They'd have to be kept alive," she said. "Polyjuice requires fresh material. If their kidnappers were intelligent, they would still be so. As a bargaining chip, at the very least. What were they after?"

Milo shrugged. "Couldn't say, really. Some kind of magic book they thought I had. Could be my spellbook..."

"Your spellbook?" McGonagall asked.

"Ah. Right. Well..." Milo decided that, in this case, perhaps honesty was the best option. "I'm not a wizard like you, Professor. I don't have a mental block in Transfigurations; I just can't do your sort of magic."

"So, the story you told when you first arrived really is true?" she asked. "You're from another world?"

"Yup."

Surprisingly, she threw back her head and barked a short, loud laugh. "Believe it or not, that is not the most surprising thing I've heard today. We'll have to cancel your remedial Transfigurations classes, I suppose. Albus knew about this, I presume? Of course he did. Very well. He decided you ought to continue attending this school, and I will not alter that decision. However, be advised that I will not be going easy on you in class because of your... differences. I will not pass a student who cannot meet certain minimum standards. How you meet those standards are up to you, however."

"Understood," Milo said.

"Now, this... spellbook. What would they want with it? What would happen if they were to obtain it?"

"Nothing," Milo said. "It's just so much paper to them. Booby trapped paper, at that. Maybe they wanted something else, though. They weren't terribly clear, to be honest. High on gloating, low on clarity."

"That sounds like most dark wizards I've had the poor fortune to meet," McGonagall said. "So. Death Eaters have kidnapped my students, infiltrated the school, and launched an attack in my tower?" McGonagall stood up, her knuckles turning white as she trembled with slowly growing fury. "If they think I'm just an old schoolteacher who will roll over and let them get away with this, they've got another thing coming. A very large, very heavy thing, transfigured into existence, perhaps, directly above their heads." With visible effort, she calmed herself down. "I believe, Mister Amastacia-Liadon, that the time has come for you to tell me everything. I presume that, much like last year, you have allowed curiosity to get the better of yourself and have been looking into this matter on your own time, against quite literally dozens of school rules and regulations?"

"Well. Yeah, basically."

"Good lad. Twenty points for Gryffindor. No, make that thirty. Take me to your Death Eater," she said. "Let's see what we can learn from him—or her. Fill me in along the way."

Chapter 14: Cacophony in C Sharp

Hogwarts has always been a notoriously difficult structure to get around in. Rooms sometimes shuffle about when nobody is looking too closely, corridors appear and disappear based off of the phases of the moon, the day of the week, the hour of the day, and, in one notable case, the lowest factor of Ravenclaw's current house points. There were walls pretending to be doorways and doorways pretending to be walls. Pathways from commonly used room to room were handed down, year to year, within houses. Secret passages, trick doors, and the patterns of moving staircases were valuable commodities that could save days of time over the course of a student's seven-year career. Two rooms close enough to share a common wall could require several solid kilometers of winding hallways to reach each other, while two other rooms on the far sides of the castle could be only a few minutes apart if they shared a direct passageway. To make matters worse, there had been a rash of disappearing corridors over the past few days.

The result was that the time it took to walk from classroom A to classroom B had very little to do with their actual geography, and more to do with one's knowledge of the school's hidden ways and the sheer mental strength it took to commit them all to memory.

McGonagall walked through the school as if she was born there. She walked straight through solid-seeming walls, ignored inviting-looking hallways, said cryptic phrases at random-seeming statues and suits of armour, and, once, had to turn around and walk backwards down some stairs for no obvious reason.

It had taken Milo half an hour to walk from the staircase that led up to Gryffindor Tower to the Headmistress's office.

McGonagall led them back in under a minute.

"—and that's how I defeated the Death Eaters and damaged the tower," Milo explained. "And before you ask, don't worry. The trap will only trigger once; it won't go off on the other students."

"Make no mistake, Mister Amastacia-Liadon, we are not yet finished with this subject," McGonagall said archly. "You are not to go leaving booby-traps in this castle, is that clear? No matter how safe you think they are. The possibility of accident is far too great."

Milo sighed. "Yes, Professor."

"But for now, I believe, I shall simply say: well done. I can't think of many grown witches or wizards who would have been able to not only escape from that situation, but send the Death Eaters packing. However, would it not have been more expedient to simply capture them? Every Death Eater in Azkaban is a Death Eater we don't have to worry about."

"Well..." Milo frowned. Why hadn't he captured them? It would have been easy. They were injured; he could have held them down with Evard's Black Tentacles, or simply the threat of further Explosive Runes, until help arrived. He hadn't even considered the idea. Had he simply failed an Intelligence check?

"Still, I can hardly blame you for panicking, all things considered. No matter; they'll be found." It was a statement that left no room for compromise, uncertainty, or alternatives. Milo reminded himself of which House it was that McGonagall was the Head.

Mordy sent a wave of alarm through their empathic link.

"Boss! We got incoming!" he said, poking his furry little nose out of the pouch that was his home. He sniffed at the air a few times with his goggle-enhanced nose (yes, the goggles improved his sense of smell, because magic). "Whatever it is, it smells dreadful. Oh, and it's huge."

Milo shook his hands out of his sleeves.

"Professor," he said. "We're not alone."

McGonagall narrowed her eyes and drew her wand. "Explain," she said briskly.

"It's a bit hard," Milo said. How do you go about explaining that you have a psychic connection with a sapient rat that could smell danger? Oh, right. "I have a psychic connection with a sapient rat that can smell danger," Milo said. "And danger is coming."

Something tickled Milo's ears; a soft, gentle sort of caress, like a whisper without words. Had it not been for his familiar, he doubted he would have heard it at all. Having the rat within arms' reach created a connection of some kind that, using both of their eyes and ears, amplified his senses. He wasn't quite certain how it was supposed to work, as the descriptive fluff for the ability was scant. Something Harry said once came to mind...

"Tongues," Milo muttered.

"soo... hungry..." came a voice like dry autumn leaves brushed against oiled silk. "must... feeed..."

"Unless you mean 'must feed me,' I wouldn't try it," Milo shouted back at the seemingly-empty hallway. McGonagall shot him a sharp, perplexed look. "Or you'll soon find that an eighth-level Wizard is no easy meat. Back off." If he could just draw it out somewhere visible...

"You're a Parselmouth?" McGonagall asked.

"No," Milo said. "I can just use magic to talk to anything in its own tongue."

"It's own tongue? That means..."

"...the master? no... this voice lacks the Power... imposter... pretender..."

"Milo! Close your eyes and keep them that way if you value your life!" McGonagall commanded. With a flick of her wand, torches fell from the walls and flared up, creating a ring of fire surrounding them. With another movement, thousands of tiny, horizontal filaments of stone stretching from wall to wall raised up an inch off the ground from the stone floor and hung there, suspended tightly from the walls. Milo peered closer, and found that rather than stone, the threads more closely resembled lute strings of varying key, though he couldn't imagine what for. A third wand movement pulled dozens of razor-sharp, mirror-bright daggers from the wall that remained floating in front of her, trembling with power as if straining to be released. "Close your eyes!" She said again.

"But—"

"Obscuro," she said sharply, and Milo found himself with a soft blindfold wrapped around his face. He struggled and pulled at it as best he could, but it seemed firmly stuck to his face.

"What the Hells is this?" Milo sputtered. Was this another surprise Polyjuice attack? He didn't have a trap prepared, this time. Not here, anyway. Maybe he could—

Milo's thought was cut off by the most horrible, screeching cacophony that he had ever heard. It made the audio havoc of a half-orc War Chanter playing Dirge of Discord on a rusty Gehennan Morghuth-Iron fiddle with a bandsaw for a bow sound like a master elven court Bard Inspiring Heroism with a celestial harp accompanied by a chorus of Astral Devas.

"Got you now," he heard McGonagall say over the din, followed by a series of tiny thunderclaps and a roar of pain. Milo clutched his hands over his ears. He was having a serious reversal of opinion about the relative pros and cons of Familiar-amplified hearing, though it did allow him to catch McGonagall mutter something about "infinite points from Slytherin if I make it out of this."

Is she winning? Should I help? What's happening? Milo was going crazy with curiosity, tinged with panic. Clearly, this was Slytherin's monster—but what was it? Judging by the fact McGonagall blinded me, it's probably safe to say it Petrifies by a Gaze attack, Milo thought. So, I can't look at it with my own eyes. I can't use Chain of Eyes, because the only nearby options are Mordy and McGonagall, and both would be Petrified if they looked at the monster. I can't cast Arcane Eye because it takes ten minutes...

It occurred to Milo that he had made a very large, very irritating oversight. Uncanny Forethought, the feat that allowed him to cast any spell he knew in six seconds, allowed him to cast any spell he knew in six seconds—regardless of the original spell's casting time. He could have saved literally days in Scrying over the last month had he paid closer attention to the wording.

"Arcane Eye." An invisible magical sensor winked into existence at Milo's shoulder, feeding him whatever it saw, and what it saw was carnage.

A roaring inferno billowed smoke into the hallway, obscuring vision and casting everything in a hellish red glow. McGonagall stood in front of Milo with her eyes firmly shut, a cloud of daggers hovering in front of her. Through the fires, Milo could just barely make out some kind of moving shape. As the beast moved, it made a horrible screeching noise akin to demon claws on a chalkboard. It took Milo a moment to realize what was happening—the creature's every movement was playing a wretched dirge on McGonagall's lute strings. At every noise, McGonagall made a sharp movement of her wand, firing a handful of daggers at the source, each marked by a sharp snap as they flew through the air. More flew from the walls, ceilings, and floors near her, creating a steady stream of supersonic blades.

It didn't take long for the monster to cotton on to what was going on. The noise stopped, and Milo's imagination filled in the blanks: the monster (which, in Milo's mind, was a spidery, tentacled abomination like you'd find in the Far Realm, if you were mad enough to go there) was holding itself perfectly still to conceal its location, waiting for its moment.

McGonagall very clearly had no intention of giving it one. Whenever it so much as breathed or twitched, the strings wailed in protest, and there was a satisfying burst of thunderclaps as she attacked the source of the noise.

Curious for a better look, Milo commanded the sensor forwards. It flew unharmed between the daggers and through the flames, ignoring the heat and smoke altogether. It breached the flames, and Milo looked up—

Yellow eyes.

Darkness.

Milo thought for a moment that the monster had eaten the sensor, or perhaps used some sort of darkness spell, and tried commanding it to retreat. It was then that he realized the spell was simply gone. Was it somehow antimagic? Or...

...was the gaze of Slytherin's monster deadly enough to kill a spell?

"Boccob," Milo breathed. Something tickled the back of his mind, something about the cry of the Mandrake...

Milo dismissed the train of thought from his mind. He'd come back to it later, after the encounter. Near him, McGonagall was breathing hard and heavily. The rain of daggers had gone from a rapid staccato to uneven, carefully picked shots. In a sudden flash of insight, Milo realized what was happening. The monster was toying with her, wearing her out. Slytherin's monster was preparing to strike. Milo had to act, fast.

It was time to unleash some asskicking most Arcane.

But to do that, he had to determine what it was—and he was starting to get a pretty good idea. They'd ruled out the idea before because this creature's form of Petrification simply paralyzed people instead of turning them to stone, but the evidence was becoming increasingly conclusive in spite of that. The Parseltongue, the association with Slytherin, the heraldry of the house. Everything pointed to one thing: snakes. Maybe its gaze wasn't turning people to stone, but Milo had long since learned not to rely heavily on preconceptions carried over from his universe.

"I know your name, monster," Milo whispered to himself, drawing a mirror from his Belt. He'd been carrying it around for years, intended to ward off vampires. It was also handy for looking around corners without risking a headshot. But here, Milo thought it would have an even more potent effect. "Arcane Eye," he muttered to himself. Another sensor appeared at Milo's side, this one carefully positioned to avoid looking directly at the fires and the beast that lurked behind. There was only one snake that could kill with a glance, the Queen of Serpents herself. Of course the rumours of her death had been greatly exaggerated. They generally were, in Milo's experience. "Mage Hand." The small steel mirror floated away from his gloved hands, using the sensor to guide it.

The steel mirror crossed the line of fire, blackened by smoke and heat around the edges slightly.

Despite everything, Milo felt himself grinning. It wasn't every day that you got to kill a being of myth and legend with nought but a Cantrip and a pair of Divinations. He held the mirror in the air for a moment, pivoting it around to cover every angle.

"Eat reflective payback, Medusa!" Milo snarled. He dismissed the Mage Hand to follow it up with overwhelming fire and explosions. It was the only way to be sure. The mirror fell to the ground, but Milo didn't realize his error until it had already touched the ground.

The mirror triggered the lute strings. Milo heard McGonagall intake her breath in a hiss, and refocused her attention on an area several yards to the left of where the Medusa lurked, firing off another burst of daggers. It would only take a moment for her to realize the error, but if the monster was quick enough, a moment was all it would need. Still, Milo reminded himself, that left the flames to protect them.

...unless, of course, Slytherin's monster proved willing to get a little singed.

"No!" Milo cried.

Something leapt from beyond the flames. Something scaly and dark. Something almost, but not entirely, unlike a Medusa. Before he could either avert his gaze or get a clear look, he lost connection with his second Arcane Eye. He heard McGonagall let out a sudden, sharp cry of pain, then fall silent. The blindfold around his eyes loosened, no longer glued to his face with magic. Milo pressed his back even further up against the wall, trying to make himself as small as possible, while he listened for the monster. However, even with his familiar-enhanced ears, now that the monster was outside of the string-covered area, he couldn't hear so much as a whisper of scale against scale.

Not that, when it really came down to it, it mattered.

The beautiful thing about magic—well, one of the beautiful things about magic, after the versatility, power, style, and mystique—was how indiscriminate it was. He didn't need to aim.

"Glitterdust!" For once, being blindfolded was something of an advantage, as Milo was not subjected to the blinding light of his own spell. "Evard's Black Tentacles!"

It took Milo a moment to realize that he wasn't yet dead. Had he managed to disable the monster with the tentacles, or was it simply waiting for him to take a peek?

"Detect Thoughts." Milo had no intention of attempting to listen to the creature's dark designs, but at the very least the spell would tell him if it, or any other mind capable of thought, was still nearby.

Aside from Mordy, the spell found no matches. Milo breathed a sigh of relief, sagging to the floor. He was going to live to see level nine. He was going to—

McGonagall.

She'd been—should have been—in the spell's area.

Milo tore the blindfold from his face, dismissing the tentacles as he did so.

The Headmistress lay on the floor, mirror clutched in one outstretched arm, the other soaked in blood. She was deathly still.

"Boccob, Fharlanghn and Pelor," Milo cursed, running up to her.

Milo didn't have any actual skill ranks invested in Heal, but with assistance from Mordy and the Healer's Kit he kept on hand, he could get by at some simple tasks. He'd made a point over the last year to do some research on basic human anatomy of the residents of these parts, whose physiology seemed to operate under bizarre and overly complicated and seemingly contradictory rules far inferior to his own streamlined and logical Hit Points system. After all, how did it make sense that two injuries that dealt the same amount of damage would have result in different severities of injury just because one was Bludgeoning and one was Piercing? This universe's blatantly unbalanced favour of edged weaponry was part of what convinced him to pull the Mirror Move trick to become proficient with his sword.

The point was that, thanks to his diligent research, keen perception and instincts, finely honed mind, assistance from a supernaturally intelligent rat as a nurse, and finely crafted first aid kit, Milo was able to hazard a guess that the oozing, swollen, inflamed bite on the Headmistress's blood-soaked wand arm was Very Probably Bad News.

"Can you walk?" he asked her, to no response. He frowned, and checked her pulse. He didn't get one, but wasn't certain if that was because there wasn't one to find, or if he'd failed a check. To see if she was breathing, he reached for the mirror to hold it over her mouth. It wouldn't budge, she was holding on to it so tightly. Words like 'death grip' came to mind, but with effort he dismissed them. Panicking would do neither of them any good at this point.

He gave the injury another look. It didn't seem to be bleeding, which was odd. From what he'd seen of the locals—images of Hannah, bleeding helplessly in the snow flooded his imagination—they tended to bleed like crazy from injuries of this magnitude. To Milo's kind, blood was largely cosmetic. It was a sign that said, depending on one's perspective, 'I'm injured, heal me!' or 'I'm injured, finish me off!' It served to enhance drama and tension. Blood in this world, near as Milo could tell, served a more direct purpose in keeping bodies functioning. Blood loss wasn't a sign of a problem so much as it was the problem.

And McGonagall wasn't losing any. And she wasn't breathing. And she wasn't moving.

Milo could practically hear the copper piece drop. Slytherin's monster—Milo didn't know what it was, but he was now pretty sure that it wasn't a Medusa—had bitten her on the wand arm. Judging by the whole snake-motif-thing and the nature of the wound, it was likely highly venomous. Milo didn't know if that meant it would have killed her in hours or minutes or seconds, but McGonagall had clearly deemed it life-threatening.

So she'd grabbed the mirror, and looked into the reflected image of the monster, Petrifying herself. Petrified people didn't eat, didn't breathe, didn't age, and, Milo was willing to bet, wouldn't succumb to poison or disease.

"Clever," Milo whispered in admiration. I guess you don't get to be the Deputy Headmistress in a world-renowned school of witchcraft and wizardry by collecting bottle caps, he thought to himself. "Levitate." McGonagall floated a few feet off the ground, completely unmoving.

Milo walked behind her to the Hospital Wing, gently pushing her as he went. I spend altogether too much time Levitating people to the Hospital Wing, he reflected. Then he frowned. Reflected.

Why had McGonagall bothered with the mirror? All things considered, it would have been far easier in the time she had available for her to simply look up and meet the gaze of the monster.

He was beginning to get the feeling that they'd been operating under a fundamental misunderstanding of the creature's capabilities.

Hermione had been diligently researching the creature for weeks, without success. Nothing Milo had read in his Scholar's Touch-fuelled-speed-run through the library seemed to match, either. This creature, whatever it was, was powerful enough to kill a spell with a look, was venomous enough that McGonagall, likely the most skilled transfigurer alive, was forced to deliberately send herself into stasis rather than, say, transfiguring the venom inside of her into water.

Perhaps they'd been searching using the wrong criteria. The most prominent feature of Slytherin's monster was that anyone who saw it was Petrified, and both he and Hermione had been searching first for a list of magical creatures with that ability, then trying to determine which of them the monster was.

But what if Slytherin's monster couldn't Petrify with a gaze? If that was all it took, McGonagall wouldn't have bothered with the mirror.

As Milo hurried down the hallway pushing the injured McGonagall, he became increasingly certain that he was right. The Petrification was a distraction. What else do I have to work with? Milo's mind raced. It speaks Parseltongue, so it's either a snake, or it, like me, has certain Polyglot talents. It's venomous, fitting with the whole snake thing, so that's a start. Unfortunately, there were thousands of completely nonmagical venomous snakes Milo could think of, much less magical ones. Venom was kind of what snakes were famous for. Milo glanced at McGonagall's wounded arm. Venom.

Milo threw open the doors to the hospital wing.

"What is the meaning of—" Pomfrey demanded, then froze when she saw McGonagall. "Oh, Minerva," she sighed. "Just, er, float her over to this bed, will you?"

"It bit her," Milo said rapidly. "So don't wake her up before you can figure out what to do about that. Gotta run, bye!"

"Wait, boy!" Pomfrey shouted, but Milo had already broken into a dead sprint to the library.

He might not know what the monster was (yet), but that didn't mean he couldn't find out where it lurked. And Slytherin's monster had given him a way to do just that—but he needed to make some preparations first. He'd learned (the hard way) that, sometimes, rushing in blind and unprepared was the exact opposite of what one did when one desired to survive to be able to cast ninth-level spells.

He was just rounding the last corner when a hill giant threw a boulder at his chest. Milo lost balance and fell painfully to the ground with a curse. A huge, tawny owl Milo had never seen before stood on his chest, a roll of parchment tied to one leg.

"Just what I needed," he muttered. "More complications." Milo untied the roll, looking at it carefully. It was on thick, white, expensive parchment and sealed with green wax bearing an unfamiliar sigil with a familiar name:

DEPARTMENT OF MAGICAL LAW ENFORCEMENT

Underneath, written by hand in similar-coloured emerald ink:

URGENT

Chapter 15: Not So Subtle

Author's Notes: Essay, Exam, and Holiday Season is finally over, so we can now go back to our regularly-scheduled fanfiction.

"Did you see that?" PC Travis asked, peering through the binoculars into the sky.

"See what?" Fiona asked distractedly, focussing her attention on the Dursley's front porch.

"An owl," Travis said. "Don't often see them places with this many people, and in broad daylight no less."

"Would you focus?" Fiona asked. "We're only posing as birdwatchers."

"Speak for yourself," Travis said defensively. "I've been a member of the BBC for five years."

Fiona couldn't help herself. She lowered her binoculars and stared at him in the face.

"The BBC? Next you'll say you voice the Daleks." She raised her binoculars again. "What does that even mean, anyway?" she added, mostly to herself. "Being a member of the BBC. They're not a club, you know."

"No, it's—"

"Still, make sure you put in a good word for me with Tom Baker next time you see him." Fiona couldn't see Travis's face because she was staring through her binoculars, but she was fairly certain he was rolling his eyes.

"It stands for the British Birdwatching Community," Travis said through clenched teeth. "And Tom Baker hasn't been the Doctor since 1981."

Fiona grinned. "He'll always be my Doctor."

They'd been doing this for the better part of a month, now. Sometimes they were birdwatchers, sometimes they were a young couple looking to buy or rent a home, sometimes (when they were on duty) they just drove past in their patrol car trying to look casual. Well, as casual as you can look driving a police car in a neighbourhood like Little Whinging. They had to work this around their regular duty schedule, which made things even more difficult. And then there was the nagging fear that they had found what they were looking for, but had been made to forget...

"Hold up," Travis said slowly, peering through his binoculars. "I don't believe it!"

"What?" Fiona asked. Had they finally made their breakthrough? "What do you see?"

"That's a Guatemalan Pygmy Owl!" he said. "They're terribly rare—even in Guatemala! I wonder how it got to Little Whinging?"

"Hey. Focus," Fiona urged. "We're looking for clues, not owls."

"Clues as in articles and goings on of a suspicious nature?" Travis asked in a strange voice. He still hadn't moved his binoculars from above the house across from the Dursleys'. "Possibly related to undertakings criminal and, in our case, potentially arcane?"

"Yes, which you bloody well know," Fiona said irritably.

"Then maybe you'll be interested to hear that this particular owl has a newspaper tied to its leg."

Travis and Fiona lowered their binoculars and looked at each other for a moment, then were in their car—a beat-up, lime green loaner from PC Harris—and gone in seconds.

A few minutes, a change of outfit, and a phone call later, they pulled up in front of Mrs. Figg's house in their patrol car.

Fiona knocked on the door.

"She won't answer," Travis said. "She's not home. We saw her leave not half an hour ago."

"I know that," Fiona said. "And you know that. And all the nosey neighbours of Little Whinging know that," she said with a pointed glance at Petunia Dursley, who was peering at them from over her just-painted white fence (some dastardly individual, it appeared, had defaced it with cryptic writing in the dead of night), "but they don't know that we know that. So we knock, first."

After waiting what Fiona judged an appropriate amount of time, they opened the door and walked in.

"Aren't we breaking the law?" Travis whispered. "I feel like, maybe, we aren't supposed to do that. We're sort of supposed to do the opposite of that."

"Nope," Fiona said. "Because not five minutes ago the police received an anonymous tip-off of that a suspicious person had illegally trespassed into this residence intent on committing criminal acts. As the closest available officers of the peace, it's our duty to investigate. Make sure we search thoroughly; he could be hiding anywhere."

"We did?" Travis asked. "That's rather convenient, wouldn't you say? Did we get a description?"

"Suspect has a black waxed moustache, a black domino mask, a black top hat and a bag with a green pound sign stitched on it."

"Ah," Travis said. "One of those anonymous tip-offs. Just goes to show that you should always lock your door when you leave."

Fiona grinned. "If you don't, anyone might wander in."

The first thing Fiona noticed—as well as the second, third, fourth, and fifth thing—was the cats. There was a tabby on the dresser, a calico on the table, a pair of white ones on the rug, and an enormously fat grey one on the mantle.

Every single one was staring at them silently with large, unblinking eyes.

"Well thank God that's not too creepy or anything," Fiona muttered.

"Maybe we shouldn't be here," Travis said, eyeing the cats nervously.

Fiona shook her head. "We have a job to do, Constable. If this is the house of our perp—or someone who can lead us to him or her—we need to risk it. Besides, Hannigan knows we're here. In case anything... well, just in case." In case anything happens to us, she'd been about to say. They both had a pretty good idea of what 'anything' that would be.

Fiona had expected, going in, that they'd have to search the house top to bottom to find something suspicious. She'd expected it to be well hidden, innocuous at first glance but sinister on closer inspection. In all honesty, she'd secretly expected a bookcase to open a secret door. Something, you know, magic-y.

She hadn't expected it to be sitting on the top of the morning mail.

"Bloody hell!" She exclaimed when she saw it, recoiling.

"What?" Travis asked, then followed her eyes. He stared at it silently for a moment, then shrieked.

"Stand back," Fiona said, then drew her billy club and poked it gently. Nothing happened. With a nervous swallow, she drew her white latex gloves from her belt (she'd never tell any of her co-workers, but she always thought of it as her utility belt) and picked it up. She half expected it to explode or speak or hex her or something.

"What..." Travis stammered. "What do we do with it?"

"It's evidence," Fiona said. "Hard evidence." With this, they'd have little trouble convincing anyone of what was really going on.

In her hands was a broadsheet, printed on stiff, slightly yellowed paper. The lettering was ever-so-slightly uneven and blotchy, but otherwise, it looked remarkably normal, if old-fashioned. It reminded her a little of the commemorative Armistice Day edition of The Times that her great-grandfather had framed in his little flat up north.

But this paper wasn't The Times. The large-print header declared itself The Daily Prophet. The front-page headline read: HOGWARTS' CHILDREN MISSING, with the subtitle, LOCKHART ON THE CASE. Tucked away in one corner was an article saying DUMBLEDORE SACKED, subtitled, HEADMASTER DENIES ACCUSATIONS OF GROSS INCOMPETENCE.

All of that was a little bit odd, but the weird bit—the really weird bit—were the pictures. There were large headshots of the eight missing children on the front page staring up at her. Literally staring. The pictures actually moved to follow her, as if someone had managed to turn the paper into a tiny television set. All except for the one captioned Luna Lovegood, that is, which was running around in her—its—little picture with a net, as if chasing something no-one else could see. They looked almost alive.

A frightening thought struck Fiona.

"H—hello?" she said to the paper hesitantly. Blessedly, none of them reacted to her voice. The implications of that would be significant, to say the least.

It wasn't long after the shock wore off that the anger crept in.

"Fiona—Sergeant—are you feeling quite all right?" She dimly heard Travis ask.

Loki wasn't a wizard. Loki wasn't a family of wizards.

Loki was a community of wizards.

Wizards that had children.

And they'd lost them.

"They have magic," she whispered. "Magic, Constable. And what do they do with it? Do they solve world hunger? Do they cure AIDS? Cancer?"

"To be fair, we don't really know if they can do those things," Travis countered in a reasonable voice. But Fiona didn't want reasonable. She wanted justice.

"But we sure as Hell know they can erase memories. How many wars could you solve just by making some warlords forget their reasons for fighting? By making people forget their hatred?"

"But didn't you say just last week that tampering with memories was akin to murder?" Travis pointed out quietly. Fiona chose to ignore him.

"They could just wave their hands and, poof, solve the world's problems. Some, at least. But what do they do? They break into houses and mess with our heads to cover their tracks and they lose children." Fiona took a deep breath, trying to calm down. Her gloved hands were clenched to fists. She tossed Travis the paper before she wrinkled or tore it in anger.

It was all so stupid. The paper said the children had already been missing for over a day, now. Most missing persons, if they weren't found in the first forty-eight hours, were never seen again.

"They could have come to us," she muttered to herself. Finding lost children was, in part, what the force was for. And, over the years, they'd gotten very, very good at it.

"We'll catch them, Fiona," Travis said.

Fiona's mind was already racing.

"Yes," she said. "Yes, we will. Get in touch with your friends at the BBC. We have work to do."

o—o—o—o

As it turned out, if you knew what you were looking for and had several hundred local birdwatching wackos (Fiona called them 'enthusiasts' on the rare occasion she found herself within earshot of them) at your disposal, witch hunts were surprisingly easy. Fiona shuddered to think what the Spanish Inquisition, expected or no, could have gotten up to if they'd been given a pair of binoculars and a floppy tan hat.

The Daily Prophet was, as its name suggested, delivered by owl (Owl!) every day to at least several dozen homes in the Surrey area, but probably several more. After asking around, Travis found that they were not the first to discover these messenger owls, who had first been seen in numbers in 1981. There was that year again. 1981. Between the wizards and the Doctor, it was a bad year all around. Something significant had happened then, but Fiona was at a loss as to what.

The owls weren't just used to deliver the paper, either. Owls had been spotted all across Britain carrying perfectly normal-looking postage. This, like most things surrounding these wizards, irritated Fiona. Regular, non-magical people had gone through great efforts to set up a perfectly functional national postal system, but apparently that just wasn't good enough for wizards. No, they disdained the delivery network of the common masses and used their own private owl-based system. In any case, how the Hell did the owls know where to go? It made no sense.

Confusing as it was, it was also an enormous weakness. You don't have to be a hardened outlaw or covert operative to know that, when trying to maintain a low profile, daily avian post drops could be something of a hindrance.

"If they have papers," Inspector Hannigan said upon seeing the Daily Prophet, "they have a society. And if they have a society, they have morons. And if they have morons, then we have a way in."

"By finding those morons and getting answers out of them, sir?" Fiona asked.

"No, Sergeant. Not by finding the morons."

It was then that Hannigan told Fiona his plan.

She liked it immediately.

The Daily Prophet, like most newspapers, had a letters-to-the-editor page where readers could send short letters, mostly to complain about being referred to as 'wackos' instead of 'enthusiasts.' In small print at bottom of the page was an address to send those letters to:

777 DIAGON ALLEY
LONDON
UNITED KINGDOM

That wasn't the only place 'Diagon Alley' was mentioned in the newspaper. There were ads for shops, which sold everything from ice cream to cauldrons to 'magical' pets. Magical. Pets.

She loved Sprocket well enough, but if she could replace him with a magical talking version that could open tins for himself, she'd do so in a heartbeat.

There was no record, and never had been, of a street named 'Diagon Alley' in London—or anywhere else in the country, for that matter. The alley was invisible, unknown. A ghost.

The only way to find it would be to ask someone who knew.

It took them three days to put together everything they needed, and another two weeks for their wackos to find them a satisfactory mark. They didn't tell the birdwatchers why they were looking for owls in the middle of the largest metropolitan area in the country, of course, but that didn't stop them from helping. They just subtly encouraged the idea, which was already floating about, that they were the descendents of secret messenger owls used carry secure information in WW2. People will sometimes resort to the most desperate of excuses to avoid facing the truth in front of them: that magic is real.

And it is weird.

From there, it was simply a matter of going door-to-door. Nobody answered until the fifth one—not terribly unusual, considering it was the middle of the working day.

"Hello?" came a quiet, sleepy sort of voice, followed by a loud sneeze. The door opened a crack.

"Mister... Fortescue?" Fiona asked. If they were right in their theory, this man had the information they needed. However, he would also have access to mysterious and largely unknown powers. Fiona couldn't help but hope, just a little bit, that they were wrong.

"Aye," he said, then sniffed. "Who wants to know?"

"We three seem to be, ah, lost," she said. "Could you perhaps point us in the direction of," she swallowed, "Diagon Alley?"

An immediate change came over Fortescue. He opened the door the whole way and smiled. He was a middle-aged man with a large black beard, dressed in a housecoat and fuzzy slippers.

He looked the three of them—Fiona, Travis, and Hannigan—up and down for a moment.

"A bit foreign, are you?" he said. "I'd be there myself, if not for this nasty cold. Just head right a few blocks—careful crossing the street, the Muggle drivers are madmen, all of them— and turn left on Charing Cross, then keep walking until you see the Leaky Cauldron. If you're a squib—are you a squib?"

"I beg your pardon?" Hannigan asked.

Fiona hesitated. What on God's green earth was a squib? She doubted he was referring to the explosive.

"No matter, terribly rude of me even to ask. Anyway, if you're a squib, you might not be able to see it at first, but its right between a Muggle book shop and a record place. You can ask Tom how to get in from there."

They thanked him and said their goodbyes, all but running back down to the street.

"Well, that was easy," Travis said after they were well out of earshot.

"Too easy," Fiona grumbled.

"When you have as much experience as I have in the force and in life, Sergeant," Hannigan said, "you'll learn that it is impossible for something to be too easy."

They followed his directions—earning more than a few peculiar glances from passersby—and immediately encountered a problem.

Quinto Bookshop and the record shop shared a wall. It was quite impossible for there to be a pub between them.

"Do you think it was a trick?" Travis asked. "Maybe to get rid of us while he calls for reinforcements?"

"If so, he's a very good liar," Hannigan said. "My gut says he's on the level."

"He said we might not be able to see it," Fiona said. "Guess he was right."

"Maybe we have to do a spell to get through?" Travis said.

"He would have told us," Hannigan said.

"Not if he thought it was obvious."

Fiona scratched her chin, thinking. There didn't seem to be anything unusual about where the buildings joined, but on the other hand, there wouldn't be, would there? Whatever had bewitched the Leaky Cauldron had kept the ordinary citizens of London out this long.

"We could stake the place out until someone else goes through," Hannigan suggested. "And see how that person does it, then follow."

"Maybe there's a door, but it's just hidden?" Fiona suggested. They were so close. She didn't want to wait for another lengthy stakeout. She wanted in now.

"Wouldn't help if it was bloody invisible," Travis said. "There's no room for it. It's impossible."

"Says the man who's trying to find a magic door," Fiona said. "Right. So let's just assume for a moment that nothing is impossible, and that there really is a door here. We just can't see it. So how about we just..." Fiona closed her eyes and took a step forward, into what her brain said should be a solid wall. She collided with something—but it wasn't a wall. It felt like heavy, solid wood. She reached around at waist level until her hands grasped a heavy brass knob, and turned it. Then she took a step forwards and opened her eyes.

The place was old. Like, really old. Fiona had been to actual ruins that looked newer than the Leaky Cauldron. The walls were crumbling old plaster, a heavy chandelier hung from the ceiling, its candles giving off dim light. There wasn't even a hint of anything electrical to be seen. Mismatched wooden tables were scattered throughout the room seemingly at random, with chairs all of different heights, styles, and centuries of origin set around them. The pub was largely empty, save for the tall, pale, hunched man with pointy ears behind the counter and a grimy, robed figure hunched over a mug, which, upon close inspection, had actual mist pouring out of it.

Hannigan and Travis followed her after a short delay.

"...makes no geometrical sense!" Travis said, before opening his eyes and looking around. "Oh," was all he managed to say.

"Shall we go talk to Nosferatu over there, then?" Fiona asked quietly.

"Count Orlock," Hannigan muttered. "Nosferatu was the name of the film."

"Good morning!" the barkeeper said in a surprisingly cheerful tone of voice.

Fiona and Travis had spent days on their disguises. They only had a few scant pictures from the Daily Prophet to go by, and had to make up the rest largely with guesswork based on the theory that the folklore about wizards and witches was a distant reflection of the actual, real-life wizards and witches—which seemed plausible, but by no means certain. Fiona had gone full Granny Weatherwax: heavy black boots and pants, long black, tattered dress and a pointy black hat, with large brass buckles strewn about more or less at random. In one hand she held her broomstick—well, almost a broomstick. Sprocket had coughed up a hairball on her actual broom just that morning, but what she had was probably close enough. She hoped.

Travis, on the other hand, had gone for a more Merlin-inspired look: long purple robes and a purple hat, all with golden stars and moons poorly stitched on. He was carrying a magicky-sort of book in one hand, which was really an Encyclopedia Britannica with the cover filed off.

Fiona and Travis had had to take time off of work sewing, stitching, and hunting down costume supplies. But Hannigan... well. Hannigan had thrown his together quite quickly. Suspiciously quickly, in fact.

It was almost as if he already had his costume, and had been just waiting for an excuse to wear it.

"What do you mean?" he asked from behind a bushy, fake white beard. "Do you wish me a good morning, or mean that it is a good morning whether I want it or not; or that you feel good this morning; or that it is a morning to be good on?"

The Count Orlock-lookalike blinked his huge, dark eyes and stared at Hannigan for a moment, taking in his worn grey robes, his wide-brimmed grey hat, and his gnarled wooden staff.

"I meant, did you want a bloody coffee, a brandy, or a beer?" Orlock said irritably.

"Er," Fiona interjected. "None for us, thank you. We were actually just on our way to, ah, Diagon Alley."

"Oh, why didn't you say so? It's just out the back." He pointed at a crooked, worn back door.

The three cops said their thanks and left through the door.

"Oh, bloody hell. Not another one of these," Hannigan muttered.

Behind the door was a solid brick wall.

"Pft," Travis said dismissively. "We know how to deal with these now." He closed his eyes and confidently strode into the wall, purple robes flowing billowing behind him dramatically. He then promptly bashed his forehead into the wall and reeled backwards, clutching his head. "Uh," he said. "Does anyone have a plan-B?"

Hannigan shrugged. "Same way crooks get into apartment buildings. Everyone tie their shoes."

Sure enough, after only a few minutes, another patron of the Leaky Cauldron walked through, gave them a passing glance, and stood before the wall. He tapped the bricks a few times in several places, and the wall vanished.

"Excuse me!" Hannigan said, leaping up and sticking his hand through the open space. "Yes, thank you. Sorry." The stranger walked through the doorway and left them.

The three of them looked at each other for a moment.

"I half expected you to look at the wall and say mellon, Gandalf," Fiona grinned.

"Do not meddle in the affairs of wizards," Hannigan said in a booming voice. "For they are subtle, and quick to anger."

"Half right ain't bad," Fiona countered.

And just like that, they were in.

Chapter 18: The Boy Who Lived

Author's Notes: Big hand to Estroll, everyone, who's taken it upon himself to translate Harry Potter and the Natural 20 into Chinese. The URL can be found in my profile.

Needless to say, this is just about the coolest thing that happened since I found out I was on TVTropes.

o—o—o—o—o—o

Gilderoy Lockhart yawned as he walked back to his office, flexing his sore shoulders. He'd had a long day, between his lengthy correspondences to Rita at the Prophet, trying to spin Dumbledore's string of fiascos to put himself in a good light. He'd already half-convinced her that the only reason more students hadn't gone missing was because he'd personally uncovered and run off their kidnappers. Then there were the constant messages from the DMLE demanding more information about the kidnappings, as if he knew anything. Honestly, it would be so much easier if the kids had just been killed. Then people would stop asking him to mount a rescue mission...

An idea struck him. A little false evidence here and there, a few altered memories, and people would come to that conclusion without his needing to suggest it. And if they did miraculously turn up eventually, Lockhart was certain enough of his skills that he could take credit for that, too. A nice footnote to his already glamorous career at best, avoiding a difficult investigation and potentially hazardous situations at worst.

But all of that could wait until tomorrow. Tonight, nothing would stand between Lockhart and a cup of hot tea, his stack of fanmail, and a good night's sleep.

Lockhart narrowed his eyes as he reached his office door. He had been about to turn the knob and enter when he noticed something awry.

Ever since the delinquents that made up this school's student body had begun leaving stink bombs in Lockhart's office every few weeks, he'd started taking extra precautions. The students would expect magical countermeasures and perhaps come up with workarounds, so Lockhart had resorted to a more mundane solution. Besides, he wasn't certain he was capable of some of the spells required for long-term, reliable security. Rather, he'd taken to leaving a hair wedged between the door and the frame when he left.

The hair was on the ground.

Lockhart drew his wand, opened the door, and sprang through, hoping to surprise the crook mid-act.

It was not a student that Lockhart found in his office.

"H-headmaster," Lockhart stammered. This he had not been expecting.

Snape was sitting in Lockhart's chair casually, as if this were his office and Lockhart was the intruder. He looked Lockhart up and down as if he were something unpleasant Snape had stepped in.

"To what do I owe the pleasure?" Lockhart asked, recovering, he hoped, smoothly. With a deft twirl, he sheathed his wand.

"I think you quite know why I'm here," Snape said.

"Oh?" Lockhart raised one eyebrow.

"I'm here to deliver a warning," Snape said. "Your first and your last." Snape lowered his voice to a deadly whisper. "I know, Lockhart. I know everything."

Lockhart's pulse raced. He could feel his heart beating against his chest as if it wanted to break free and escape. How had Snape figured it out? He'd been so careful. So bloody careful! He had to play for time. Maybe he could catch Snape by surprise and make this problem go away entirely.

"I'm not certain I understand," Lockhart lied.

"Don't bother denying it," Snape snapped. "The evidence is quite clear. You made a grievous mistake the moment you applied for this job. If you've got something to hide," Snape said in a tone that could freeze an inferno, "don't become the Defence Professor of Hogwarts. It'll come out eventually."

Lockhart moved his hand to his wand as casually as he could, trying to disguise the motion as a scratch.

"I wouldn't try it," Snape said, raising his arms from below the desk. He'd had his wand in hand the whole time, trained on Lockhart under the desk. "Let's not escalate this further. The only reason I haven't revealed your secret yet is that, frankly, I didn't care. But your continued presence is fast becoming inconvenient."

"I... see," Lockhart said. "Let's pretend, for a moment, that you were correct. What is the point in confronting me like this?"

"To tell you to stop. Now. Presently, I'm content to let the past stay that way—the past. But if there's even one more, I might give the relevant authorities the hints they need to connect the trail of victims to you. Or I might come for you myself. I have yet to make up my mind. Are we clear? Yes? Good. Dismissed."

Lockhart had already left before he realized that he'd just been kicked out of his own office. He wondered where he was supposed to go now.

One thing was for certain, however: it was high time to update his resume.

o—o—o—o

The four of them—Hermione, Milo, Harry, and Ron—walked out of the library despondently. They'd given up in disgust as, once more, their research efforts proved fruitless.

Harry scratched at a bandage wrapped around his head.

"I can't believe Snape banned our Quidditch gear," he complained. "A quaffle did this. A quaffle!"

"Just be glad it wasn't a bludger," Ron said. "At least you're conscious enough to complain."

Harry had been hit in the head by a carelessly-thrown quaffle in practice that morning.

"That's my exact point," Harry said. "A quaffle was all it took. Quidditch is bloody dangerous. Bloody Snape. I hate that oily, arrogant, petty git."

"Did somebody say Draco Malfoy?" said an (unfortunately) familiar voice. Shortly after, an (unfortunately) familiar boy stepped around the corner, flanked by his usual cronies.

"Bloody hell," Ron muttered.

"What do you want this time, Malfoy?" Harry asked impatiently.

Draco leaned with his back against the wall, twirling his wand idly between his fingers.

"Oh, I think you're well aware of why I'm here, Potter," he sneered.

"Yeah, Potter," sneered Crabbe. "You know why we're here."

"Yeah, Potter," sneered Goyle. "You're cognizant of the grounds for which we are here."

Idly, Draco tossed a brightly wrapped sweet over his shoulder, which Goyle caught, unwrapped, and swallowed with practiced speed.

Hermione rolled her eyes. "We don't have time to play your little games, Malfoy. Why don't you run along and make someone else lament your existence? Just this once?"

"It's too late for that, I'm afraid," Draco said. "You've fallen directly into my trap!"

"What?" Ron asked bluntly.

"I laid a trail of breadcrumbs so subtle and intricate that you followed them, like a rat—pardon the expression, Weasley—sniffing out a particularly delicious bit of cheese, or a shark smelling a drop of blood in the ocean. But you didn't realize that I'm the shark, now did you? The shark guarding the cheese. Only there is no cheese. No. Cheese. At. All." Draco narrowed his eyes menacingly. "Only the shark."

"Mate," Ron said, "you seem a bit confused."

"Should I take him?" Milo asked Ron, Harry, and Hermione. "Or does one of you want to?"

Draco, not to be stopped by interruptions or badly mixed metaphors, steamrolled on obliviously. "It was all me!" Draco declared. "And now it's the end for you!"

"It was you?" Milo asked, genuinely shocked. "You're the—"

"Of course it was me!" Draco said. "The notes slipped under the door? The clues in the Prophet? The dust in the footprints? The missing pages from the library? The Mandrake root in the sweets? All me!"

"Mandrake root..." Harry heard Milo whisper.

The noise of Harry's, Hermione's, Ron's, and Milo's eyes simultaneously closing and opening in a quadruple blink of surprise was very nearly audible.

"I warned you not to come back to Hogwarts this year," Draco hissed. "I told you it would go badly for all of you. That the most fiendish plan ever concocted by any witch or wizard, living or dead, was in motion against you. All of you. And now here it is!" Draco paused, as if expecting something to happen. His grin slipped slightly as he waited in silence.

"In the name of the gods above and below," Milo said, "what the hell are you talking about?"

"Ah..." Draco stammered. Evidently something was supposed to happen, but hadn't. Harry was hardly surprised; Draco's 'plans' rarely seemed to go as, well, planned. After several profoundly awkward seconds, he rallied. "You may think you're some bigshot, Potter, just because people say you killed He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named as a squealing baby," Draco spat.

"What?" Milo said suddenly. Harry glanced over at Milo, who had a peculiar expression on his face.

"If no-one minds," Harry said, drawing his wand. He'd had just about enough of this. "I think I'll handle this one."

"But you're nothing," Draco continued. "Nothing. Everything you are, everything you're so bloody famous for, was handed to you! You're completely defined by somebody else's achievements! You'd be nothing without the Dark Lord! Just a normal, stupid-looking kid with messy bloody hair and a knack for sticking your nose where it's not wanted."

"I'd have parents," Harry said through clenched teeth. "Which, need I remind you, is all you seem to have. Now run along before I do something you regret."

"Oh, that's it!" Draco snarled. "Crabbe! Goyle!" he barked at his henchmen. "Stop messing around and do it."

But Crabbe and Goyle didn't answer. In fact, Harry realized, it had been a long time since either of them had said anything.

"Hey, Milo," Harry whispered, turning to the side. "I think..." But Milo was gone. Harry frowned, looking around. He was nowhere to be seen. His pet Mordy, looking slightly confused, was standing in his place.

o—o—o—o

Fiona heard the tires screech in protest as Hannigan slammed on the breaks, bringing the car to a sudden stop in the snow. The seatbelt locked, pulling her tight against the stiff chair. Hannigan had committed at least seven misdemeanors, not including the numerous laws of physics that must have been broken to get them into London so quickly.

"Right," he said. "Everybody out."

Whoever was in charge was clearly taking this seriously. Paddywagons and the new Armed Response Vehicles were scattered about in the staging area set up nearby the target, but out of sight. Heavily armed officers dressed head-to-toe in black milled about, checking their weapons and equipment, or simply pacing about to keep warm in the icy air. Other units would be cordoning off nearby streets to keep civilians out of the way before the raid, and there were even a few ambulances parked nearby, just in case. Fiona couldn't see them, but she knew that marksmen would be stationed on nearby roofs and in upper-storey rooms.

Hannigan led them to a small cluster of men gathered about some large radios on light folding tables that served as a makeshift command post.

"Hannigan!" greeted a tall, clean-cut, rail-thin inspector. He was handsome, in a severe sort of way. His sideburns were trimmed so sharply that Fiona felt they should be registered as a lethal weapon. "Better late than never, I suppose."

Hannigan shrugged. "Naturally. Knowing your parties, I figured it'd take at least a few hours for things to move past the 'showing-off-the-new-doilies-and-curtains' phase." He yawned. "Looks like I was right." His face broke into a sudden grin, which he hid poorly. Despite their words, it was pretty clear that they were old friends. "Been what, six months, McTavish?"

"Eleven," McTavish said. "And it was years, not months." He beckoned for them to follow him a few yards away from the radio crew. "Are we certain this is for real?" he asked, his voice lowered.

"Positive," Hannigan said seriously.

"Right," McTavish said, running one hand through his close-cropped, graying hair. "I had to hear you say it in person." He made a vague gesture at the men surrounding them. "They've been told. They didn't believe me at first. I passed around that... newspaper... your lot found, but a lot of them are still half-convinced it's some kind of trick. That it isn't real. I don't think they want to believe it's real." Fiona was pretty sure McTavish's men weren't the only ones who didn't want this to be real.

"If this goes smoothly," Hannigan said, "then it won't matter."

"I take it you have some sort of plan, then?" McTavish asked.

"Sergeant Smythe here has been studying our perp's... abilities," Hannigan said. "She'll brief you."

Fiona swallowed. Even after all the time she'd been spending around Hannigan recently, she still wasn't particularly comfortable speaking with the brass.

She took a deep breath and spoke. McTavish's face became increasingly pale as Fiona worked her way from a selection of minor hexes and jinxes, up to the three allegedly 'Unforgivable Curses.' If they're so unforgivable, Fiona wondered to herself, how come so many of these murderers are still walking free?

To her surprise, McTavish didn't raise a protest at some of the more extraordinary facts Fiona mentioned. "That actually explains a lot," he said. "Back in the early 80s, we turned up dozens of bodies with no apparent cause of death. They were perfectly healthy—except for the minor inconvenience that they were stone dead. It also explains how they stayed hidden for so long." He sighed. "Partly."

"Sir?" Fiona asked. "I'm not certain I follow."

"Say you could just use magic to control a small number of people completely," McTavish said. "Either by this... this imperious curse, or by magical incentives—cures for sick relatives, magical blackmail, that kind of thing—how would you keep thousands, or maybe millions, of people hidden?"

Fiona's eyes widened. "You think they got to the PM?"

"I would," McTavish said. "And some of the people who actually do things in government, too. It would also explain why all of these 'mysterious deaths' were so lightly investigated. If I were them, I'd hang on to the Commissioner like a lifeline." He straightened himself up. "But none of this is directly relevant to the task at hand. What do you recommend?"

"Shock and awe, sir," she said. "Get in there and get him in custody before he even realizes what's happening, much less has time to do sorcery."

"Then what?" McTavish asked. "Say we bag him. What's to stop him from just leaving after?"

"Sedatives, sir," Fiona said. They'd come up with this one in the car. "The book I read said Apparating takes great concentration. Keep him too doped up to try it."

"You do know we can't just drug people, don't you?" McTavish pointed out. "We do have to follow some rules, after all."

"We can if we deem him a danger to himself and others, sir," Fiona said. "Which shouldn't be too hard to swing. After all," Fiona grinned wickedly, "he seems to think he's a wizard. Clearly delusional, sir. Maybe dangerously so. Then we explain to him—slowly, and in small words—that we'll go to the press if he doesn't co-operate. His own people will string him up if it gets to that."

McTavish smiled, despite himself. "I like your style, Sergeant," he said. "There may be a bloody knife fight over who gets to keep you, after this is all said and done. Ever fancy a gig in the big city? Think about it."

"I..." Fiona stammered. She wasn't quite certain what to say.

"No, you don't need to answer just yet. But either way, I want you coming in with us. You're the only one here with a real idea of his capabilities, and we might need you."

Fiona hesitated.

"I know it's not exactly by the book," Hannigan said. "But nothing about this operation is. Are you in?"

"Yes, sir," she said. "Wouldn't miss it."

"Right." McTavish said as if there was no question in his mind as to what her answer would be. "Best get suited up, then."

o—o—o—o

Milo raced through the hallways as fast as he could. It was all so obvious; he couldn't believe he hadn't put it together before now.

It was the Mandrake root that should have tipped him off, months ago. He'd been so caught up looking for a creature that could Petrify that he'd forgotten, once again, that he was in a different world, now. A world with Mandrake roots. Mandrake roots that killed with a cry... or, with slightly faulty protection, knocked people unconscious. It had seemed so unnatural at the time, but Milo hadn't been able to put his finger on the reason why until right now. With the exception of spells that dealt damage, almost every single magical effect in the world—in Milo's world—was all-or-nothing. You're stunned or you're not. You're trapped or you're not. You're blind or you're not.

But this was a world with failure in degrees. The Mandrake could kill you, or knock you out, or stun you, or just make you uncomfortable, depending on the degree of exposure.

Slytherin's Monster was the same as the Mandrake root. It could Petrify you—but that wasn't what it was famous for. Nobody wrote about how it could Petrify, because that so rarely happened.

If you took Petrification out of the equation, it was obvious. Incredibly obvious. Resistance to magic? Speaks Parseltongue? Venomous bite?

Slytherin's Monster was a Basilisk.

Despite the danger, despite the urgency of the situation, and despite the pain in his legs as he ran, pushing the limits of his pitifully poor Constitution, Milo felt remarkably calm.

"Circle Dance," he cast for the second time, indicating the direction of the Basilisk and allowing him to triangulate its position. The spell didn't create an image of the creature—he didn't need that, now that he already knew what it looked like—so its Gaze effect wouldn't kill the spell, as it had when he'd tried to Scry it.

Everything seemed, for the first time in months, crystal clear.

Milo had a monster to slay. He was prepared for this. He was very, very good at defeating monsters.

As he ran, Milo removed his Hairpin of Intelligence and placed a bucket over his head, tightening the chinstrap carefully. The bucket—actually a Blindhelm—had no eyeholes, and completely covered his face. However, the magic of the helmet allowed him to see perfectly, and actually enhanced his senses. He became aware of everything within five feet of him, whether he could see it or not.

But that wasn't the reason he'd made it. It was his ace in the hole against Slytherin's Monster: the helmet would prevent him from making any sort of eye contact with the Basilisk, thus, in theory, making him immune to its gaze attack. Against a traditional gaze attack, from Milo's world, it only provided moderate resistance. But all of his research on the vision-based magic of this world indicated that a selectively-transparent object, such as this helmet, should do the trick.

This was going to be almost too easy. Without its most powerful weapon, the Basilisk would basically just be a big snake. Milo would pin it down with tentacles, blind it with Glitterdust, and summon a couple of skeletal trolls to finish the job. The Basilisk could wear its fangs down to nubs on them futilely; he doubted even its venom would be able to kill what was already dead. That snake wasn't going to stand a chance.

Milo would find it, kill it, and be back before Draco had finished his rant.

The spell led him to the entrance of a girl's washroom. Milo barged in, heedless of the improprieties of the situation. It was unoccupied—no students or giant snakes in sight.

"Spontaneous Search," Milo cast. A rush of information flooded his mind. He knew, suddenly, that there were six bathroom stalls (of which all but one were out of order), six mirrors (which were coated in dust), five hundred and seventy-four tiles on the floor (of which seventy-seven were cracked), and five sinks.

Milo frowned. Five sinks? There were clearly six in front of him.

He took a few steps closer, examining the sinks. To test them, he turned the handles on each. All but one faucet started pouring water.

Milo looked closer at the apparently-broken sink. The faucet had a tiny snake carved onto it.

Could this be the entrance? Milo was willing to bet, platinum to coppers, that the way to open it was with Parseltongue, as he and Hermione had worked out.

Milo only knew one Parselmouth, and he wasn't here right now. Fortunately, that wouldn't be a problem.

"Tongues," Milo muttered. "Open up."

The sink began to move. It sank smoothly, silently into the floor, leaving a massively oversized pipe in the floor leading into pitch darkness.

"Dancing Lights," he cast, sending four bright pinpoints of light racing ahead of him.

Milo stopped, on the edge of the pipe. Should he turn back and return with his friends? On the one hand, he'd learned several times over that teamwork was essential. But what he was heading into was dangerous. Like, really, really dangerous. He only had one Blindhelm to protect him from the Basilisk's gaze. A slight misstep and they could die. And, near as he could tell, if someone from this world died, they stayed dead.

No. Milo would handle this one alone. He was ready for it.

Milo reached into his Belt of Hidden Pouches and retrieved his rope (fifty feet of silk, adventurer standard-issue), tied it to an exposed pipe, and lowered himself into the darkness.

"Major Image," he whispered, sending an exact likeness of himself down the rope ahead of him. Most predators hunted primarily by scent, which the improved version of Silent Image he'd learned for Hannah's Christmas present last year could replicate convincingly.

Despite everything, Milo smiled.

That oversized snake wasn't going to stand a chance.

o—o—o—o

Draco waved a hand in front of Crabbe's face.

"Hellooooo," he said. "Earth to Crabbe."

Crabbe didn't respond. In fact, he didn't move at all.

A horrifying thought dawned on Harry.

He made eye contact with Hermione. Her eyes were wide and her face pale. That was all the confirmation he needed.

"Everybody, close your eyes!" he shouted, clamping his shut. "You too, Malfoy!"

"Oh, come now," Draco said scornfully. "You don't seriously expect me to fall for that, do you?"

Mordenkainen sniffed at the air once, twice, then scurried into a decorative suit of armour with the sort of speed brought on by pure terror.

"Ssso clossse... ssso warm... ssso tasssty..."

Chapter 19: The Boy Who Didn't

In 1976, the Who were declared the record holder for the loudest rock band in the world after a concert in Charlton. They held that record for eight years until they were barely beaten out by metal band Manowar.

Fiona's mother was at that concert in Charlton and sat right by one of the speakers. She'd never fully recovered hearing in her left ear, and often claimed that sometimes, on a silent, windless night, she could still faintly hear "Baba O'Riley."

If all twenty-seven thousand members of the audience were carrying an active, gas-powered chainsaw, the combined noise would be almost half as loud as that heard by Fiona's mother.

If every show ever performed by the Who had been as loud as the one in Charlton, their combined noise would be one hundred thousand times louder than the level required to cause nausea. It would be fifty thousand times louder than the point at which your vision starts to blur. It would be ten thousand times louder than the point at which your throat is vibrating so hard you can no longer swallow. It would be one hundred times louder than the point at which glass shatters. The noise would be so loud that, beyond simply being deafening, it would destabilize the fluids in your ear, inhibiting your balance as if you were on the far side of a bender worthy of the rock band in question.

It would have been almost as loud as the noise produced by the flashbang grenade thrown through the window of the grimy, prewar brick house.

And that's not even getting into the flash part of flashbang. Let's just say, for the sake of brevity, that it was pretty gosh darn bright and leave it at that.

Klaxons and auto alarms across the neighbourhood blared in protest and lights flicked on in windows all down the street as the residents were disturbed from their slumber.

Before their perp would have any chance to recover, nine of London's finest (and Fiona, bringing up the rear) stormed in, leaving the cheap wooden door hanging on its splintered hinges. More police were outside, securing the back or blockading the front to catch runners. Not, of course, that it would help much—these wizards could flee without needing doors.

"POLICE!" someone bellowed.

Inside was a single black-robed figure, sprawled out on the floor. Carrow, presumably.

Every man and woman of the team had already memorized the layout of the building, so they broke into three prearranged teams to clear the remaining rooms while Fiona cuffed the one on the ground.

It is a common misconception that police around the world read from the same script when making an arrest. It had got to the point that there was a traditional response among Fiona's coworkers in Staines when, in a movie, a British copper read someone their very-American Miranda rights. That response was throwing popcorn at the screen followed by humming "God Save the Queen," for reasons no-one still around could remember.

There was a script they were supposed to follow, however, although Fiona may have editorialized it somewhat.

"You're under arrest under suspicion of murder, conspiracy to commit murder, witchcraft, carrying an offensive weapon, having an offensive face, being an ugly git, being a part of a criminal organization, and for numerous general counts of being a really obviously bad guy. You have the right to remain silent, but anything you do say—what was that?"

The dark wizard groaned inaudibly.

"You say you're resisting arrest?"

The wizard moaned in discomfort, his eyes unfocussed and dazed. His ears were bleeding slightly.

"You say you're a danger to yourself and others? That you need to be sedated for your own safety? Well, if you insist. How convenient that we all just so happened to be issued just such a drug in addition to our standard equipment. Must have been in error. I'm sure the guys in Logistics will sort it out. But in the meantime..."

Fiona shot Amycus Carrow full of enough juice to down a rhinoceros and called in the arrest on her radio.

"Some great and powerful dark wizard you were," she added. "Bit disappointing, really."

o—o—o—o

Milo crept along through the Chamber quietly, Thinblade of Warning held tightly in one hand. His identical, illusory doppelganger walked twenty feet in front of him, looking—and smelling—identical to him, surrounded by the four glowing pinpoints of a Dancing Lights spell. He was protected by as many magical defences as he was capable of, though, as always, he was uncertain of the practical effects of, say, a high Armour Class in battle with an opponent who didn't seem to have an Attack Bonus at all.

Stone pillars lined the hallway, carved with hollow-eyed snakes that seemed to move whenever he looked away. There was a weird, greenish glow in the place with no discernible source, except for the obvious: magic. Aside from the light and the serpentine columns, the vaunted Chamber of Secrets seemed to be sort of plumbing nexus, which suited Milo just fine. He'd first cut his teeth in adventuring in a sewer full of kobolds, after all. Of course, back then he'd had a Rogue, a Cleric, and a Fighter backing him up. He sometimes wondered what had ever happened to Wellby, Gerard, and Zook. What had they done after defeating Thamior? He knew Wellby, their Rogue, was planning on discovering some long-forgotten draconic heritage and dipping into Sorcerer, despite Milo's urgings to the contrary. With the sort of regular adventuring Milo had been denied in this bizarre world, Wellby was probably well on his way to maxing out Unseen Seer by now.

If he ever did make it home, Milo would probably have to do some serious grinding to catch up.

Milo shook his head, focusing on the task at hand. He could daydream about his home later.

The fact that the Basilisk lived in Hogwarts' sewer system explained the smell that Mordenkainen had picked up. The snake couldn't simply use Prestidigitation to maintain perfect hygiene, the way Milo could.

Milo kept walking, hiding in the shadows behind his illusion, when he encountered a dead end.

This he hadn't been expecting. It was a sheer stone wall behind a hideous statue of a rail-thin, bearded fellow in robes. Probably Salad Tsar Slytherin himself, Milo figured. He'd walked the length of the Chamber, but he hadn't found the snake. Could he have missed it somehow? Were there secret, branching corridors? Maybe he should walk back to that weird door with the snakes and the emerald eyes. Maybe he'd missed something. (He hadn't missed the emerald eyes themselves, naturally, which currently sat happily inside his Belt of Hidden Pouches and would do so until he next found a shop).

"I think it's about time we had a chat, face-to-face, you and I."

Milo whirled around. Behind him, a tall, black-haired boy was leaning casually against a pillar, idly twirling a wand between his fingers. He was, quite simply, beyond handsome.

Handsome in the way that nothing that was entirely, good-old-fashioned, vanilla human could ever be.

His face was perfect. His face was perfectly symmetrical, his hair was perfectly combed, his skin perfectly clear. Even his robes were perfectly ironed. Perfect, as if painted by a middling artist. Good enough to look just like a human, but not good enough to look like a person. The boy looked... unfinished. There wasn't a freckle, pimple, pore, or any sort of blemish on him.

A middling artist... or a dabbling illusionist.

o—o—o—o

Slytherin's Monster was on them.

That much was obvious to Hermione.

She'd heard it slither past just a moment ago, hissing as it went. It had almost knocked over the decorative suit of armour she was hiding behind, which, unfortunately, she shared with Draco Malfoy. Mordenkainen the rat sat on her shoulder.

"What's going on?" Draco whispered.

"Shhh!" Hermione hissed.

Harry and Ron were hiding in an identical alcove just across the hall, or, at least, had been running there last time Hermione's eyes had been open.

If only she could figure out just what the creature was. It mostly sounded like a basilisk—the sheer size of the creature, based off the noise it made, backed that up—but basilisks killed people with a look, they didn't Petrify them. Milo, who had handled most of the research on the monsters in the first half of the alphabet, had insisted it couldn't possibly be a basilisk. If only she could somehow ask McGonagall, she'd seemed to know immediately what it was.

And, for that matter, how was the bloody beast getting around? The monster sounded enormous. It would be noticed immediately if it just slithered down the main hallways, so it had to have some alternate route. Of course, Hogwarts was chock full of secret passages and rooms. For all she knew, it could have its own secret network riddled throughout the school, connected to the Chamber of Secrets at its heart. Or, actually, maybe the Chamber was a network of secret tunnels.

She dismissed that train of thought. If the Chamber was so massive and pervasive, it would have been discovered long since, secret or no. Heck, the damage done by the Troll last year would probably have revealed it.

More likely the monster was utilizing a more obvious way of sneaking around. A second set of passages that mirrored Hogwarts' actual hallways, that allowed one to pass unseen. One that people couldn't—or wouldn't use.

The answer to that question was fairly obvious. Well, obvious to her, at least. The pipes. There were multiple bathrooms on every floor, and some places, such as Snape's potion dungeon and the greenhouses, had additional requirements for water. The monster could be moving unseen through the pipes of the school, where nobody would think to look.

No, that was ridiculous. There wasn't a chance that a creature as big as this one could fit through ordinary plumbing. She'd seen the pipes in the walls and under the floor when her parents had renovated their house three years ago. An ordinary snake would have trouble fitting through most of those. Could the monster perhaps shrink?

Unless...

Hogwarts was magic to the core. The lamps and torches on the walls never needed relighting or replacing. The hinges never needed oiling. The paintings never faded.

And the toilets never, ever backed up.

Could it be that the pipes themselves could expand? It wouldn't even be that hard. If a simple Growth Charm in Transfigurations could double the size of a rat, why couldn't one double the width of a pipe? It would have to detect when the pipe was blocked and expand as needed, increasing the complexity slightly, but that was hardly beyond the skill of the founders.

Especially if one of them had ulterior motives.

Expanding pipes was only one possibility. Likely the founders had access to spells with capabilities Hermione had never even heard of.

But the closest bathroom was on the far side of the floor. It didn't explain how it could get close enough to Petrify Crabbe and Goyle without being spotted by anyone. Well. Anyone who spotted it would be Petrified or dead, but surely someone would have seen the bodies by now.

Hermione frowned. Could the monster have another set of secret passages?

There used to be a little-used hallway that ran right from the girl's bathroom on this floor to the library. It was a handy shortcut she used on long days spent in the library.

But the hallway had been one of several that disappeared in autumn. Flitwick had still been unable to determine what had happened to them; it was written up as typical mysterious Hogwarts behaviour.

But what if that hallway was still there? What if it was just... hidden?

A horrible thought struck Hermione.

Milo had used his illusion magic to hide several hallways, hadn't he? It was one of the precautions he'd taken in securing their War Room.

Where was Milo, anyway?

o—o—o—o

"Who the hell are you?" Milo asked, his words muffled somewhat by the magic bucket on his head. He was well aware that he looked patently ridiculous, but, in fairness, he hadn't expected to encounter Mr. Charisma down here. He hadn't exactly dressed for company. Besides, this boy, whoever he was, would make even high-level, ultra-fashionable Bards and Sorcerers insecure.

"I," the boy said, "am Tom Riddle."

He said it like someone might say 'I am your King,' or even 'the Lord, your God.'

"Is that supposed to mean anything to me?" Milo asked. "Because I still have no idea who you are." Or what you are. Still, the name did seem familiar.

"But I know exactly who you are," Riddle said. "Milo Amastacia-Liadon, Wizard from beyond. The boy with no past, and no dreams beyond power. The Sorting Hat made a mistake, with you. You would have done very well in my house."

It didn't take a genius to figure out which house that was. "You're the Heir of Slytherin," Milo said.

Riddle bowed in a manner so elegant it would have shamed the knights of Myra (City of Light! City of Magic!). "The one and only," he said, then laughed. "Miss Granger was wrong, you know. There aren't thousands of us. The line of Slytherin was never a prolific one. There are but seven of us."

"How do you know what Hermione said?" Milo asked.

"I listened in," Riddle admitted. "Terribly rude of me, I know. It's a flaw I have."

"Are you... a ghost?" Milo asked. It was the only way he could see Riddle managing to spy on him without getting caught. Ghosts can move through walls, so, if Riddle was a ghost, he could simply lurk inside the wall, out of sight.

"A ghost? No. Not a ghost. A memory. Preserved in a diary for fifty years."

"Oh, you have got to be kidding me," Milo said.

"No," replied Riddle. "I'm quite serious."

"I would like to register a complaint," Milo said to the ceiling.

"Oh? I'm all ears," Riddle said.

"No, not with you. I'll get to you in a minute." Milo said, still looking up. "This was poorly foreshadowed! Who the hell is this Riddle character? What happened fifty years ago? What in the Prime Material plane does it mean to be a memory of all things? For gods' sakes, at least when I went up against Quirrell, I knew who the hell he was, at least. Bad form."

"Who are you talking to?" Riddle asked. "You must realize your gods can't help you here."

"Screw the gods," Milo said to Riddle. "I'm going over their heads. The DM really fumbled this one."

"DM?"

"Dimensional Maestro. Whatever. Bring out your damn snake so I can kill it, already."

"My Basilisk isn't here right now," Riddle said.

"Of course it is," Milo said. "I used magic to pinpoint its location. It's in this room somewhere; there's no use hiding it."

"The Basilisk is on Hogwarts' second floor," Riddle said matter-of-factly. "It's in the hallway between the old Transfiguration classroom and the library, killing your friends."

"What?" Milo said. "That's impossible. My Divinations..."

"Lied to you, I'm afraid." Riddle flashed him a smile. "Or rather, I did. I do that sometimes. It's another flaw of mine."

Milo rolled his eyes. "All right, all right. Out with it."

"Excuse me?"

"You know you want to. You've got that look. Adventurer's can spot them quicker than they can spot the Rogue going for their purses. You're just dying to monologue at me. So out with it. I even promise to say 'you fiend!' and 'you'll never get away with this!' at the opportune moments, if you want. Then I get to kill you. See? Something in it for the both of us. We both go home happy. Well, sort of."

"Why should I... monologue... when you already know what happened?" Riddle asked.

Milo rolled his eyes. "Fine, fine. We'll do it your way. So your name is Tom Riddle and you're a memory in a..." Milo finally realized where he'd seen the name Tom Riddle before. He suddenly felt very small. Very small indeed. Small and overconfident. "...in a diary."

"Now you're catching on," Riddle said.

"It was that book we found on Quirrell, wasn't it?" Milo asked. "Last year, when he went after the Philosopher's Stone. He had the diary." It all seemed so obvious, now. "That's the book the Death Eaters were after. They snuck in, posing as students, to get you."

Riddle smiled. "Go on," he said, as if talking to a favourite dog. "You're getting it, now."

"The diary that... that I..."

"Just say it," Riddle said. "The first step, when you have a problem, is admitting it, I've been told. Or was it the last step? It's the same in the end, either way."

Milo's voice fell to a whisper. He felt weak, as if the he'd been drained by a Wight. Somewhere in the unimportant background, his sword clattered to the ground. "But I was protected!" he said desperately. "I'm wearing an amulet!"

"But you weren't always wearing it, were you?" Riddle asked. "You took it off..."

"When I freed Quirrel," Milo said. He slid against the wall. Dimly, he was aware that Riddle seemed to be getting more substantial, more real, as they spoke. "I clamped my own amulet around his neck to free him of You-Know-Who's influence. I was vulnerable. I..."

"Yes?"

"I made another amulet!" Milo practically shouted, pulling it out from under his robes. The Eye of Boccob carved on the amulet seemed to wink at him reassuringly. "I'm wearing it right now!" Milo pulled himself together and stood up. He hadn't realized he was on the floor. "Kelgore's Fire Bolt!" he shouted. He didn't care that it wasn't the most efficient or effective spell. He wanted that smug, perfect face to burn.

Nothing happened.

Milo blinked. That was weird.

"Glitterdust!" Nothing. "Evard's Black Tentacles!" Nothing. "Summon Skeletal Troll!" Nothing. He didn't understand. He executed the somatic and verbal components perfectly. His Dancing Lights were still floating around, so he wasn't in an antimagic field. It was as if he was out of spell slots, but that was impossible. He'd been keeping track of them rigorously. He had plenty of spells left for today. Didn't he?

"The funny thing about your abominable brand of magic," Riddle said, "is that it's based on memory. You memorize your spells in the morning, and you forget them when you cast. You have to remember what spells you have ready and what you don't. And of all people, I know best the strength of a memory. The strength... and the weaknesses." Riddle smiled again. "In particular, memories are all too easy to... forget."

"The amulet is cursed," Milo realized. He'd had a similar idea when making amulets for the Ministry. "You made me make a cursed amulet. It works against everything but you. I did it right after I..."

"Say it."

There was no use denying it any further. Milo knew exactly what had happened.

"I cast Scholar's Touch. I read your book."

"You did more than just read it," Riddle said. "You did what nobody's ever done before. You read every page. Every page. Every possible page. Everything that I could ever say, ever do, ever remember. Everything. Every possibility. You didn't just read me," Riddle said, "you copied me."

"That's impossible," Milo said flatly. "Scholar's Touch specifically has no effect when reading a magical book. It's right there in the description."

"But I wasn't magical, was I?" Riddle said. "Not in the way the designers of that spell meant, anyway. Not magical in the way you and your... kind are concerned."

"But the creators of the spell clearly intended it to prevent this sort of..." Milo trailed off. He couldn't believe that he of all people just resorted to an argument that hinged on the intent of the text. It made him feel slightly dirty, as if he'd betrayed his core principles. In a way, he had.

Milo suddenly remembered something that made this so much worse. "The original," he said. "Ron was going to give it to Ginny."

"Just a ratty old book, now," Riddle shrugged. "I checked. Or rather, you did. One of many things you've since conveniently forgotten. I could tell you why, but, well, then I'd have to kill you."

"So why not tell me anyway?" Milo asked. "I mean, what have you got to lose? It's not like I could tell anybody, even if I wanted to." It was the bane of villains everywhere: they're all just dying to tell you their clever plans. How else will they get the appreciation they desperately crave?

"Fair point," Riddle said. "But I think the explanation would be quite wasted on you. It all revolves around souls, of course, and you know less than nothing about those anyway. Believe me, I'd know. I was in your head all year. Let's just say it takes a... special sort of ritual to split a soul, and you weren't up to it. So I was transferred, rather than copied."

"So... why?" Milo asked. "You were Petrifying people completely at random. Why bother? How could that possibly help you?"

"Why, revenge, of course," Riddle said. "As well as planning for the future."

"Ah," Milo said. "Dumbledore."

"Exactly. When it came time for my triumphant return, I would need Dumbledore out of the way. Dumbledore was always most powerful as a figurehead, a rallying point. I could simply kill him, of course, but that would just make a martyr out of him."

"So you disgraced him," Milo said. "Made him seem incompetent. Like he didn't care about the safety of people's children."

"Naturally. I can always kill him later. Then I had to take out his Deputy, because, well, she's his puppet, obviously. I wanted Hogwarts under someone more... amenable to my position. Snape would do nicely. I couldn't simply kill the undesirables, no matter how much I wanted to, or they'd close down my school. So I had to Petrify them. You would not believe the lengths I've had to go through to set that up. It was a fine line to walk, but it's quite beside the point now."

"That doesn't explain what you meant by revenge," Milo said. "Or why the Basilisk is upstairs, fighting my friends."

"Killing," Riddle snapped. "Killing your friends."

o—o—o—o

There was a crash and a series of tinkles, as if glass had been broken. Then again, and again. What was going on? What was the monster breaking? The only thing Harry could think of that was glass nearby were the picture frames, but why would Slytherin's monster attack them? Where was Milo? Had the monster got him? Was he enacting a clever plan?

"What do we do?" Ron whispered.

"I could distract it," Harry whispered back, "while you put on my Cloak and run for help. Try to find Flitwick or Sprout. Or even Lockhart, I guess."

"What," Ron said, "and leave you to get eaten by a giant bloody snake? Not likely. How about I distract it while you run for help?"

"Stop being such a bloody Gryffindor," Harry said. "I'm a better duellist than you. It should be me that fights it."

"The snake's resistant to magic and you know it," Ron said. "How about we both slink away under the Cloak?"

"And leave Hermione to the snake? Besides, Milo said magic items only work on one person."

"Then how about Draco distracts it while all three of us escape under the Cloak?"

"If only."

"Oh!" Ron said. "Use Parseltongue!"

"What?" Harry asked.

"You're a Parselmouth! Tell it to go away. Or eat Malfoy, then go away."

"Ron, you're a genius!" Harry couldn't believe he hadn't thought of it earlier. Of course he should use his snake-controlling ability to control the giant snake monster. It was blindingly obvious. He fished the Cloak out from his school bag. "Here, hang on to this," he said, pushing it into Ron's hands.

"Oy!" Harry shouted into the hallway. "Slytherin's Monster! Bugger off!"

"English!" Ron hissed frantically. "That was just English!"

Harry tried to concentrate—though he wasn't sure what to concentrate on, he'd never really been aware of when he was speaking Parseltongue and when he wasn't—and spoke again.

"Beast of Slytherin!" he tried again. "Begone!"

"Yup," Ron said. "Snake language, that time.

The sound of breaking glass stopped.

"what's this? the master? has the Power... but different..."

"I'm your master, now! Begone!" Harry shouted again. Or at least he thought he did; he wasn't entirely certain what it sounded like to Ron.

"...come out then, young master..." Slytherin's Monster replied. "...let me see you... so I will know who to spare..."

"What's happening?" Ron asked.

"It wants me to come out," Harry said.

"Fat chance of that," Ron muttered.

"Yeah..." Harry whispered back. "I have a plan. Run when you get the chance, right? Right."

"What? Hold up!" Ron said.

Harry stood up and drew his wand. The monster was obviously playing a trick on him—it had all the subtlety of a nursery rhyme villain—but he might be able to buy time enough for the others to get away.

Something hard and heavy hit him in the forehead. It was so surprising that he couldn't help but flinch.

Harry's eyes snapped open reflexively, if only for a millisecond. It was long enough, however.

He saw a snake, but not the one he was expecting.

Carved onto the back of the wooden picture frame was a small, neat glyph of a snake in sepia.

o—o—o—o

"Your name isn't Tom Riddle, is it?" Milo asked. "Not anymore."

"No, it isn't," Riddle answered, as if it were the most obvious thing in the world.

"Voldemort," Milo spat. "You're after Harry because he killed you."

It only lasted for a moment. Under other circumstances, Milo would have attributed it to a trick of the light, but it was impossible. The light here was green; there's no way it could have made Riddle's eyes flash red.

"That raving lunatic upstairs said it," Riddle said. "I thought he was mistaken, so I made you Apparate away—"

"Teleport," Milo said. "By means of the Astral Plane. Please, get your facts right."

"So I made you teleport away and interrogated you. Turns out he was right, somehow. I'd always assumed it was Dumbledore who put an end to me, the other me. He's the only one who it made even a lick of sense to have done it."

"Which explains the revenge aspect," Milo said. "That must sting, though. Finding out you'd been undone by a newborn." Milo knew he was in no position to talk; he'd been defeated by a book.

"A two-year-old, thank you very much," Riddle bristled.

"Oh, well then. That made all the difference, I'm sure. He must have over-powered you, with his superior strength and cunning."

"I'd show some respect, if I were you," Riddle snapped, brandishing what Milo recognized finally as that carried by the Death Eater he had switched places with.

"What have you ever done that deserves respect?" Milo asked. "You were defeated by an infant."

"You're attempting to goad me into rash action," Riddle said, lowering his wand. "It won't work. I'm well aware that, for the moment, I need you alive or I will cease to be."

"For the moment?"

"For the moment. Shortly, the point will be moot. I continue to grow in strength, and you will fade. In a matter of minutes, young Wizard, you will die, and I will rise again. It's been very inconvenient, operating through you. You can't do any magic—real magic—whatsoever, so I've had to rely on your inferior variety. Then there's that rat you have such an unwholesome relationship with. That pest was almost my undoing. How would I ever get you alone with it tagging along? Then you made a blunder."

"The Sorting," Milo realized. "I left him to keep an eye on it while I went to spy on Lockhart."

"And do certain other things, as it turned out. Favours for me, you could say." Riddle smiled. "You made your first visit here on that day, before returning. I implanted the idea in your head to use that rat to patrol the corridors at night, freeing you for my purposes. From that moment, your soul was mine. I could implant ideas, and smother others. Didn't you ever wonder why you never thought to investigate the last opening of the Chamber? That it never led you to that great oaf Hagrid?" Riddle grinned wickedly. "When was the last time you saw Hagrid anyway, Milo? The lack of... foreshadowing... you were complaining about earlier? That was my doing. You're mine now, freak."

"And you used me to... what, take out Peeves? For what possible reason?"

"To test my control of the Basilisk using you as a proxy," Riddle said. "If it went poorly and the Basilisk got out of control, it wouldn't do enough serious damage to have the school shut down. Well, likely not. Besides, I despise that poltergeist. There is no place for it in my new world."

"So, now what? Take out the Boy Who Lived so there will be nothing standing in the way of your return?"

"Precisely," Riddle said. "And thanks to you, I've even got my very own cell of Death Eaters, following my every order, heralding my return."

"Oh," Milo said. "Crap. That's why I let them go. You made me do it."

"And as my first act as their new leader," Riddle said, "I will sow the seeds of death and chaos. I'm afraid the Muggles are in for a bad day. Their first of many."

o—o—o—o

The other police filed back into the room, pulling down their intimidating black balaclavas, and reported. The team leaders—McTavish, Buckley, and Lyndon—said they hadn't found anyone else.

"But the kitchen was empty," Lyndon, a tough brunette who might have been pretty if her nose hadn't been so severely broken, said. "As in, really empty. Bare shelves. Didn't they say that we found this guy because he was at a supermarket?"

"Yeah..." Fiona said. "Huh." She frowned. "Did anybody find a wand anywhere? A plain wooden stick of about a foot or less?"

There was a collection of shrugs.

Fiona patted Carrow down. There was a pocket sewn into his robe that looked like it might be a wand holster, but it was empty.

What the heck? If she had a little stick that gave her unrivalled supernatural powers, she'd make certain it was always within easy reach. In fact, she'd probably get a spare, just in case.

"I think—" McTavish said. Fiona never did find out what it was that he thought, because Baldwin shot him in the head.

The lights flickered out, and there was a short series of loud, popping noises. The door slammed shut.

Then the dying started.

The world flickered green and black, like a strobe light of death.

The moment the lights went out, Fiona had hit the ground. She knew what was coming.

Some of the other officers either hadn't taken her warnings seriously, or they hadn't had the time to act. She saw Buckley and a pair of policemen whose names she didn't know—a fact she deeply regretted, now—collapse, limp.

She wasn't sure who started it, but someone panicked and started shooting. Others joined in soon after. Uneven, staccato bursts of panic fire further lit up the unnaturally dark room. She cursed whatever idiot was doing it—in the mad lighting and chaos, they were as likely to hit one of their own as... well, as whoever was doing the magic. Unless they weren't acting under their own will. She was sure Baldwin, at least, was under their spell.

There was a pounding on the front door, a solid, rhythmic sound. It took her a moment to realize it was from a police battering ram. She'd never before heard what that sounded like from this side of the door. But it meant help was coming, at least.

The pounding continued.

Or was it? It had only taken them a single hit to open the door the first time, and it had been locked. The door was a cheap, faux-wood model. No earthly force could keep intact under that kind of impact.

She was trapped.

o—o—o—o

"You've made a mistake," Milo said. "A critical mistake. Four, actually."

"And what might they be?" Riddle asked.

"Mistake one," Milo said, holding up one finger. "Snakes aren't the only animals that hunt by smell."

o—o—o—o

"Now!" Hermione shouted. She heard a slight whoosh as the rat on her shoulder fired one of his bracer-launched knuts.

Slytherin's Monster was resistant to magic. Hermione had to assume that covered Milo's sort of magic as well as her own, so monster would ignore the Explosive Runes scratched onto the knut as if it were a light sea breeze. It was a hopelessly futile plan that would, at best, distract it for a moment before it ate the lot of them.

But that was why Mordenkainen, who had pinpointed the monster by its distinctive scent, hadn't fired at the snake itself.

It had fired at the ceiling above it.

Multiple tonnes of ancient stone bricks poured down onto the monster. The dust and wind from the rock avalanche was enough to make Hermione stagger backwards.

"Did we get it, Mordy?" Hermione asked. "One squeak yes, two squeaks no."

"Squeak."

Hermione let out a breath she hadn't realized she'd been holding.

"Squeak squeak!"

She could hear stones rolling over each other, now. If only she could see. She had no idea what was going on...

A thought struck her.

"Harry!" she said. "Pass me the Cloak!"

"Uh," it was Ron's voice. "It sort of... got Harry."

"What?" Hermione was shocked. When had that happened? Had the monster killed one of her only friends while she cowered behind a suit of armour? "What do you mean?"

"He's stuck in one of those... one of Milo's amber things," Ron said. "Like the one in Gryffindor Tower."

"Then we're dead," Hermione said. She could hear more bricks rolling off of each other. One touched her foot, making her jump. That Cloak had been her only plan.

"Squeak squeak squeak squeak!" Mordy kept insisting.

"He gave it to me," Ron said. "Here..." She heard footsteps as Ron blindly staggered in her general direction. She reached about with her arms clumsily to try and find him. It was like playing a morbid game of Marco Polo.

Eventually, her hands brushed his shoulder, and he passed Harry's Invisibility Cloak into her hands.

"Wingardium Leviosa. I'm going to float this thing over the snake's head. If it's head is invisible, we don't need to worry about meeting its gaze. So, Mordy, squeak once if I should go left, twice if I should go right..." Then she realized, abruptly, how stupid that plan was. Mordy could smell, he couldn't see. There was no way he would be able to pinpoint the location of the Cloak in the air that way.

More debris rolled across the floor.

"SQUEAK SQUEAK SQUEAK SQUEAK!"

"Fire another one!"

There was second blast, and stone flew everywhere. The next thing Hermione knew, a freight train slammed into her.

Hermione was flung from her feet and landed awkwardly on her side before sliding into something solid and mercilessly unyielding.

o—o—o—o

"Mistake two," Milo said. He was lying on the ground. When had that happened? "Muggles are pretty badass." Milo had already made that particular mistake, once.

o—o—o—o

Fiona hadn't waited for the magic to start before she dropped to the ground. The visibility was poor, the situation was confusing, the enemy's capabilities were unknown and friend and foe were mixed haphazardly. It was complete, utter, merciless, unmitigated chaos.

But there was no reason that that couldn't work for her as well as it did for these wizards.

Nobody was paying any attention to her. There were people dropping left and right; what was one more harmless Muggle?

The wizards were using mobility and deception as their primary defence. They were Apparating or Disapparating or whatever whenever one of the surviving policemen or women aimed at them, and more often than not by the time the trigger was pulled, the police hit nothing but the wall. It was fast. Anarchic. They were nigh-unhittable.

But they weren't invincible.

Fiona saw Lyndon make a snap-shot connect with one robed figure's shin before he could Disapparate. The wizard's leg buckled underneath him, and he fell to the floor in a cry of pain. Another wizard grabbed the first and winked out of existence. A moment later, when he returned, it was alone.

The wizard aimed his wand directly at Lyndon's back. She would be dead in seconds, and she had no idea. There was nothing she could do, even if she knew.

Fortunately, Lyndon wasn't alone. The wizard had made the critical error of Apparating within a meter of Fiona, presuming her dead.

Fiona kicked the wizard in the knee with everything she had, which was probably overkill. Knees have to support a lot of weight but also have a wide range of mobility, and as a result they're extremely vulnerable. The kneecap popped, and the wizard screamed in agony as he fell to the ground. Fiona grabbed the wand from his hand and tossed it across the room.

A masked witch noticed Fiona's surprise attack and aimed her wand at her, already in the process of casting a spell. In desperation, Fiona grabbed the fallen wizard by the shoulders and rolled him on top of her. The wizard put up a struggle, but had absolutely no sense of the co-ordination and control needed in a hand-to-hand struggle like this. There was a green flash, and the wizard went limp in Fiona's arms.

The momentary distraction was all Lyndon needed. Her gun roared and the witch crumpled.

Two more wizards and another witch whirled to aim at Lyndon, but she dived through the door into the next room over. Green pinpricks of light shot through the open doorway after her.

That left Fiona as the only active officer left in the room. Baldwin was still standing with his gun in hand, aiming at empty space. He hadn't moved since killing McTavish. Evidently, the witch or wizard controlling him had other things on their mind. Cooper lay propped up by the door to the kitchen, bleeding from a bullet wound to the gut.

Fiona was about to die. That was the long and the short of it. There were now five cold killers of supernatural power aiming lethal weapons at her, and she was largely without cover, save for the corpse of their friend lying on top of her. She'd been told, largely from movies, that in such situations time slowed down. As if she would have the good fortune. Her heart pounded, and she could taste nothing but adrenaline. Time seemed to be going faster and faster, as if in a race with her racing heartbeat.

It was an awkward angle, but she could probably draw her handgun from beneath the dead wizard. Not that it would do much could—she was a lousy shot. Ordinary British police generally didn't carry firearms, and the only reason she had one now was because McTavish had insisted she not be defenceless. If she could just take out the one that was controlling Baldwin, then he could potentially help. Or if she got the one keeping the door closed, maybe it would allow the reinforcements hammering at the door to get in. The only problem—well, aside from those previously mentioned—was that she had no idea who it was who was doing that. Come to think of it, she didn't even know if the spell would end if its caster died.

Screw that, she decided. She had time to do one thing, and that one thing didn't necessarily need to keep her from dying. All she needed to do was distract them, and hope that Lyndon—if she was still alive—could take it from there.

Fiona ripped a flashbang grenade from her vest and tossed it in the general direction of the cluster of dark wizards and witches.

The stun grenade would certainly daze the murderers into inaction. They would be disoriented, blind, and deaf. Using magic or Disapparating would be impossible.

It was the winning move.

The only problem, a teeny little glitch in the overall plan, was that the grenade had a two-second fuse.

Fiona estimated that it only took about a second, a second and a half tops, to cast a killing curse.

"Avada Kedav—"

A gun roared once, twice, three times.

Here's the thing about gunshots. All loud noises, really. Unless you're used to them—and it's very hard to get used to them—it's extremely difficult not to look around for their source when you hear one. At the very least, its nigh-impossible not to flinch, even a little. It's a hindbrain response, a gut instinct. You can't avoid it just by being tough or menacing, you have to be trained to be used to it.

And Fiona would bet her life—was betting her life, really—that not one of these Ringwraith-wannabes had ever had their headgear slip on the firing range.

A little flinch. But when all you're aiming with is a wand that weighs an ounce or two at the largest and your hand is already shaking from adrenaline and panting and two of your comrades had just died in front of you and its dark and beneath everything you're scared...

Well, sometimes a little flinch is all it takes.

"—ra!"

Fiona kicked the dead wizard from off of her and dived left, landing in a roll. She could tell by the fact that she was still alive that the death curses had missed her.

Fiona had a split-second to remember to slam her eyes shut and cover her ears.

Then the world went white.

o—o—o—o

"Mistake three," Milo held up a third finger. He had to use his left hand to support his right, now. "Hermione Granger."

o—o—o—o

"Ron?" Hermione called out tentatively.

There was no response.

Her left arm hurt. It hurt so much that simply saying 'it hurt' seemed laughably inaccurate. It really, really hurt. The pain in her arm was her whole world. She suspected she'd been hit by one of the falling rocks.

"Malfoy?" she asked.

"Y-yes?" Draco stammered back.

"How about you run and get help?"

Judging by the footsteps, Draco was gone faster than the snacks at a ten-year Hufflepuff reunion party. Hermione wanted nothing more than to follow him, but that would leave Ron and Harry to the creature. Assuming, of course, they were alive. She only had Milo's increasingly-suspicious word that the Snake Sigil spell was harmless, and she had no idea what had happened to Ron.

"Mordy?"

"Squeak."

"Do you still know where the Cloak is?"

"Squeak squeak." Curses. It probably wound up buried, or worse, wrapped around a rock or something. It could take hours to find, if so.

"Do you have any more of those knuts?"

"Squeak squeak."

"Figures. You got anything else up your sle—"

"SQUEAK SQUEAK SQUEAK!"

The monster moved. Clearly, it had finally freed itself from the mountain of rubble Mordy had dropped on it.

A creature as big as this one seemed—and Hermione really was just guessing here; she'd obviously never seen it—would likely have a hard time manoeuvring in the narrow hallway. Its speed wouldn't help it, then. Actually, it might work against it: there was every possibility it would keep moving past her for a second or two if she could just avoid its initial charge.

Hermione, panicking, decided to roll to the left, which was sort of a mixed bag as it turned out. On the one hand, she was still alive, which meant she'd avoided the monster. On the other hand, she'd placed the weight of her whole body on her injured limb, which was bad. Really bad.

Hermione screamed and clutched her shoulder reflexively, which just seemed to make things worse. The rest of the world seemed distant, unimportant, compared to the agony of her arm.

By the time she'd managed to refocus, she'd already squandered her brief advantage.

The basilisk—she was pretty certain that's what it was, it being obvious if you ignored everything Milo had said—was coming back towards her.

Panicked, she reached about with her good arm for something, anything, with which to defend herself. It was futile, she knew, but what else could she do?

She could smell the creature, now. A foul stench of death and decay mixed with an open cesspool that made her want to gag.

She felt a crushing weight on her legs as it slithered on top of her, its hot, damp breath smelling of rotten meat. It hissed something unintelligible in Parseltongue, wrapping her up in its coils. She could imagine its hooked, fanged maw opening up to swallow her like a mouse.

Her hand grasped something cold, round, and heavy. She had no idea what it was, but she swung with everything she could, putting her whole body into it.

Snickersnack!

Hermione barely felt any resistance at all. The hissing stopped, followed by a pair of heavy thuds. Hermione shuffled out from under the still snake, finally daring to open her eyes.

The basilisk was dead. Really, incredibly dead. She doubted, in fact, that anything could possibly be more dead.

Its head was completely severed from its body; scales, flesh, and bone sheared through like a knife through warm cliché.

In her right hand, she held a ridiculously ornate sword. Its golden hilt was studded with rubies, and its blade shone like silver. It belonged in a museum, or, frankly, on the Queen's wall. A clinical, investigative part of her brain noted idly that its handle must have been enchanted—it didn't slip despite her hand being coated in sweat.

She recognized it, of course. There was a picture of the Sword of Godric Gryffindor in the chapter headings of Hogwarts: A History. She remembered thinking that it must have been an artist taking liberties; no non-ceremonial weapon would be so... garish.

Clearly, she'd been wrong. It had cut through the basilisk so cleanly that there wasn't even any blood on the blade. It was like Slytherin's Monster had only realized it was dead afterwards.

Where in Merlin's name had it come from?

She tabled that mystery for later, first going to check on Ron and Harry.

Harry was, as Ron said, trapped in the telltale amber force field of Milo's Sepia Snake Sigil. This meant, horrifyingly, that he would miss the Charms exam next week—assuming the spell would actually end when Milo said it would. Milo... she'd deal with him, later.

Ron was sprawled across the floor, an ugly welt on his head. He was breathing, but apparently unconscious. He could have serious internal injuries or a fractured skull, but Hermione wasn't certain either how to check or what she should do if he did, so decided to wait for Madam Pomfrey to handle it if Draco ever actually returned with help.

Mordy was sniffing the sword curiously. He was so coated in dust that he looked gray rather than brown. He looked slightly battered, but otherwise fine. Hermione wasn't particularly worried—Mordenkainen worked like Milo did. As long as he wasn't actually dead, he'd recover in a few days.

At some point, she'd have to find her wand, the Invisibility Cloak, give the Sword of Godric Gryffindor to the proper authorities, and explain why there was a schoolbus-sized dead snake in the hallway, but first, she decided, lying down seemed very attractive.

o—o—o—o

"Mistake four," Milo said. He couldn't even raise his hand, anymore. "Your last mistake. And it's a big one."

Riddle kicked Milo squarely in the stomach.

"And what could that possibly be?" he asked, his wand pointed at Milo's forehead. "What mistake could I have possibly made that will save you, now? The process is almost complete. Your soul is mine. All I have to do is finish you off, and I will be free, and you will be dead. You are alone. You have no weapons, no magic, no tricks, no power, and no friends. You are completely, utterly, pathetically helpless."

Milo grinned. "You'll see."

Riddle shrugged. "Crucio."

There is no adequate way to convey what the Cruciatus Curse feels like, because it doesn't feel like anything. It's easy to describe what a burn feels like because most people know what it feels like. Anyone who's learned to cook know the feeling when some boiling hot water or oil flies out of the pot and sears your arm. Anyone who's fallen on concrete knows what a skinned knee feels like.

Nobody who hasn't experienced the Cruciatus Curse firsthand—fortunately, a very small pool of people—can imagine what it feels like.

The Cruciatus Curse isn't, for example, the physical equivalent of being cursed with the last breath of a dying loved one. It isn't that because it's quite possible for the human brain to imagine what that feels like with a reasonable degree of accuracy, extrapolating from past experiences. And it isn't like being slowly dipped into boiling hot water, or like being lit on fire, because massive physical trauma will eventually sever nerve connections. At the very least, they will eventually cease functioning as intended. The Cruciatus Curse will keep your nerves functioning perfectly for the duration. The Cruciatus Curse causes the Platonic ideal of pain. All other pains are but imperfect approximations of what the Cruciatus Curse can cause.

But for all of that, it's only pain, and pain is only a feeling. Pain is a signal from your nerves to your brain for your benefit. It is to teach you that what you were doing was stupid, and you shouldn't do it again.

But people knew that, and it doesn't stop them from giving in to pain. People betray families, ideals, and nations to escape pain. But those are the people of this world, this plane.

To the people of Milo's world, pain is something else entirely.

Some feelings are real. Fear is real, and it could make or break battles. Exhaustion is real. Courage is real, and is a Bard's most powerful weapon. Temperature, hunger, and thirst are real.

But pain? Pain is imaginary. There is no status effect called 'Pain'. One of the few spells that weaponizes pain, Symbol of Pain, is deadly not for the torment it causes, but the hefty penalty to attack rolls it imposes. Pain isn't even fluff. Pain is less than fluff.

Pain is roleplaying.

Milo shut down the part of his character that cared about pain for the moment. The agony was still there, but it simple ceased to matter. He stopped thrashing around on the ground.

Riddle frowned.

"Crucio," he cast again. "CRUCIO."

Free of the pain, Milo was able to consider his plan. It was a gamble, but if it worked, it would be Riddle's death blow.

It was memory. This was all about memory. Riddle was a memory, and he was controlling Milo through his memories. Milo's memories were malleable; they could, demonstrably, be removed and altered. Riddle could make Milo forget his memorized spells (or, and Milo found this more likely but less glamorous, make him repeatedly cast them at the wall until they were gone and then make him forget).

But there was a part of every adventurer's memories that were sacred, and no force in the multiverse could affect them. The gods couldn't touch it, and not even the Destiny Manipulator had any power there.

The greatest weapon of adventurers is not their weapons, or their magic, or their skills, their feats, their powers, or their class features.

It is their backstory.

There are constraints on a backstory. A backstory cannot grant any information not represented by the appropriate Knowledge skill, a backstory cannot grant any possessions beyond starting gold, and a backstory cannot grant followers beyond those attainable by Leadership.

But a backstory can do pretty much anything else.

As long as it happened before he became an adventurer, Milo could remember pretty much whatever he wanted.

Riddle was preparing to cast his death curse, but that didn't matter to Milo. If talking is a free action, then thinking sure as hell is.

Harry Potter defeated the greatest dark wizard that ever lived using his backstory, and right now, Milo was in a position to do exactly the same thing.

All it would cost him is his mother.

All Milo needed to do was remember that his mother had given her life to save him from a dark wizard, and he was protected, the same as Harry.

He might even 'remember' that he had a cool, magic scar. Adventurers love cool scars.

That would be all it took. If Milo did that, he would walk away from this unscathed, and Voldemort would once more be defeated.

"My mother..." Milo said. Or tried to, anyway. His throat felt terribly weak.

All it would cost him was something he didn't really have to begin with. Unless he specifically remembered doing so, he effectively had no family. It wasn't as if was sacrificing anything. It wasn't as if he was killing her, was it? For all intents and purposes, she didn't even exist, yet. Most adventurers were orphans, or missing at least one parent. It wasn't like Milo would be unusual in that regard. It was easier, that way. Fewer names to think of for one's backstory.

"What was that?" Riddle asked. "Crying for your mother already, are we? I'm terribly disappointed. Not surprised, mind. But disappointed." Riddle—no, Voldemort—pinned Milo to the ground with his foot and pointed his wand directly at Milo's forehead. "No matter. Stoic or begging, It's all the same once I kill you."

Milo knew what he had to do. It was the smart thing to do. The rational thing to do. The optimal thing to do. What was one semi-existent life in comparison to the death and destruction that a second Voldemort would wreak? The choice was obvious, after weighing the pros and cons for even a moment.

Milo cleared his throat. He could taste blood. "My mother is a baker." A baker. That was good. It explained Milo's newfound obsession with sweets. "Her name is Ley Amastacia, and she's famed far and wide for her gourmet desserts." He was new at this. Untested. "She's a retired Wizard, but she refuses to use magic to assist in her baking. She says she likes it better that way, that using magic ruins the fun of it. Besides, she wants to be able to say she's the best without resorting to performance-enhancing spells. It's something I never understood until right now. But none of that's what's important. The important thing is she's happy. She misses me, but she's got my dad, my brothers, and my sisters. She's happy. She's really, incredibly, obnoxiously happy and there's not a damn thing you can do about that."

"Fascinating," Voldemort said. "Avada Kedavra."

o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: Yes, this is the end of Part Two (saving an Epilogue, coming soon), but no, it is not the end of Milo's adventures or of Harry Potter and the Natural 20. Stay tuned for Part Three, tentatively named Harry Potter and the Save-Or-Die, coming in Summer.

One fundamental flaw with traditional paper novels is that you always know exactly how close you are to the end of the book, simply by virtue of there being few pages left. In that sense, it was refreshing to write in a medium such as this, because the end could be a surprise (especially because HP books traditionally end in early summer/late spring, not early winter).

I would like to thank everybody for the awesome reviews, kind PMs, suggestions, and support! You guys are just about the best community of readers an author could ask for. It was especially fun seeing people's reactions to some of Milo's more obvious Possession-induced fumbles and their guesses as to why he would be acting that way. I branched out a little further from canon in this book, adding in a subplot with original characters (always a risk in any fan work), but I think it worked out overall, so don't be surprised if things diverge a little further in the future.

tl;dr: You guys are awesome and should feel awesome. Epilogue and sequel coming soon.

Chapter 20: Epilogue, Awakenings

Hermione realized she'd been staring at the unfamiliar ceiling for several hours without properly registering it. Or possibly several seconds. Or maybe she'd dreamed it.

Waking up is like that, sometimes.

It was then that she discovered that quite literally everything hurt.

She made an undignified groan, and realized she was in the hospital wing.

"Good morning to you, too," a voice said brightly. She recognized it immediately.

"Professor Dumbledore?" Hermione asked. The smiling Headmaster was sitting on a stool by her cot, an expression on his face that she couldn't quite place. "Wh—"

"Ah, first, may I make a correction, and then a request?" Dumbledore said.

"Er. Of course."

"I'm not, strictly speaking, a professor at the moment," Dumbledore said, "meaning you are perfectly free to call me Albus." Hermione shuddered inwardly. There was absolutely no way she would ever refer to the Headmaster by his first name. She'd ignore homework to play Quidditch, first. She felt unclean just thinking about it. "Secondly, a request: I'm not, ah, shall we say, technically allowed to be here presently. This is something of an infiltration, as it were. So I would greatly appreciate it if questions were kept to a minimum. In return, as I am a strong believer in fair exchange, I shall, likewise, keep my answers to a minimum."

"Wh—"

"Good. I'm glad we can see eye-to-eye on this."

"What happened?" Hermione said.

"Ah. Hm. That's quite a big question. If by 'what happened,' you meant, 'what happened just now,' the answer would be that we were just engaging in a dialogue refreshingly free of the typical student-teacher formality that has so characterized our past interactions. If you meant 'what happened' in the broader meaning of the word, I would say that the Earth is continuing its merry journey around the Sun, twirling about like a graceful garden gnome on its way. But if you meant, 'what happened while I was unconscious,' well, it's quite a long story. And not all of it is good news, I'm afraid."

"Then start with the good news, Prof—er, Mr. Dumbledore?" Hermione suggested.

"The eight missing children are, blessedly, safe," Dumbledore said. "It seems our photogenic Defence Professor had been investigating the issue on the side, located the house they were being kept in, and heroically rescued them himself. It's all the more impressive considering I was, of course, attempting precisely the same thing in my newfound spare time. Alas, but it appears I do not have the makings of an investigator. The Ministry snapped him up shortly after, and he's now working for them as an Obliviator. A curious position for a man of his apparent talents, but I'm told he requested it specifically. The important thing, of course, is that Hogwarts' missing children have been found."

"Fantastic!" Hermione said. "Are they all right?"

"Perfectly fine. They seem to have no memory of anything after being nabbed in the grounds, mostly near the Forest. They're with their respective families at the moment, but should be fit to return to school next week. Sadly, so many students will be absent that Flitwick has had no choice but to cancel his Charms exam next week. He was quite looking forward to it."

Well, that was three afternoons' worth of studying that Hermione would never get back. She gritted her teeth and pressed on.

"What about the Sword?" she asked.

"And to which sword would you be referring?"

"The Sword of Godric Gryffindor! What happened to it?"

"Is that what you used to kill Slytherin's Monster?" Dumbledore mused. "Most impressive. It only appears for a true Gryffindor in times of direst need, you realize. When Draco Malfoy returned with Acting Headmaster Snape, it was nowhere to be seen. There was quite a bit of disagreement as to how a Basilisk came to be so... thoroughly decapitated in the halls of the school. Most impressive. Not surprising, of course—the Sorting Hat makes its choices for a reason—but extremely impressive nonetheless. Remarkable, in fact."

"What about Ron and Harry?" Hermione asked.

"Both perfectly fine. Mr. Weasley is recovering in the cot just across from you, in fact. Mr. Potter, on the other hand, is still in the hallway trapped in a mysterious magical field. Which brings me to the sad part of the story." It was then that Hermione recognized Dumbledore's expression. It was one that she hadn't ever seen on him. It was pain.

o—o—o—o

Fiona realized she'd been staring at the unfamiliar ceiling for several hours without properly registering it. Or possibly several seconds. Or maybe she'd dreamed it.

Waking up is like that, sometimes.

She was lying in an uncomfortable bed in a room that reeked of disinfectant. A hospital, then.

She could hear the rustling of paper on paper.

"Hello?" she asked. Her throat felt dry.

"You're awake!" It was Evan Travis. She rolled her head to the side, and found him putting down a newspaper. She caught the first two words from front page headline: LONDON MASSACRE.

Oh, yeah. That.

"What happened?" Fiona asked.

"You were shot."

"What, really?" She asked. "Where?"

"Left leg, just above the knee," Travis answered.

"I never even noticed," she said. "Go figure. Is it bad?"

"You got shot. When is it ever not bad?"

"You know what I mean."

"It didn't hit an artery. Doctors say you'll probably make a full recovery, but it'll take a while and it'll suck, basically. Best find a cane you like and get used to it. You'll need to ask a doc for more, they wouldn't tell us no matter how much Hannigan shouted. Something about not being close family. We've had someone here keeping an eye on you in case... well, in case one of them came for you. We figure it's only a matter of time. Hannigan would have been here too, but... Ah. There's been an inquiry, of sorts. He's being questioned."

An inquiry. Hooboy. They all knew that at some point they'd have to pay for their repeated and flagrant disregard for the rules, but Fiona had hoped that when it came to that, they'd at least have a suspect in custody.

"Best hit me with all the bad news, then."

"When you used the stunner, the door suddenly gave. We stormed the place, but the, ah, suspects got away. Poof, they were gone."

So breaking their concentration did end the spell. Fiona filed that bit of information away for future use.

"What, even Carrow?"

"Hold on, I'll get there. When we finally got Baldwin to pull himself together and talk, he said he'd just found a side room not on the map and investigated it. That's where they got him."

"Not on the map? But we had the architectural plans! That's impossible!"

"Funny thing," Travis said, "when he tried to sketch it for us later, he couldn't."

"What do you mean, he couldn't?"

"He just couldn't. The pen wouldn't draw on the page. We went through a dozen pens and as many pencils, even a bloody crayon, and none of them worked."

"Is he still... bewitched, then, do you think?"

"Nah. When he described it, none of us could draw it. I think they did something to the room, somehow, not to us."

"So these wizards were hiding out in the secret room?"

"Not just them," Travis said. "And here's where we get to the good news. Well, good-ish. They found the kids."

"What kids?"

"The missing magic kids. They were in Baldwin's magic room. All but one, anyway. They were tied up and blindfolded, but were otherwise in perfect shape. But... they vanished the second we turned our backs on them. We had an armed guard on them and everything, but nobody saw a thing."

"Kidnapped again?" Fiona asked.

"Apparently."

"Dammit!" she said, slamming her elbow into the thin mattress. "One step forward, two steps back. At least we got Carrow." Fiona narrowed her eyes. "We did get Carrow, didn't we?"

"Ah. About that..."

"Out with it."

"While we were checking on the kids, he... changed."

"Changed?"

"Right before our very eyes. One second he was a stone-cold killer, the next he was a kid. One of the missing kids, actually. That Finnigan one."

"Where is he now?"

"Vanished with the others."

"So what did we really accomplish?" Fiona asked. "Good men and women died, for what? No suspects in custody, no real evidence found. No nothing."

Travis shrugged. "I wouldn't say that. We know that despite what the wizarding books say, they have an explicitly anti-Muggle faction still operating at large. We know they can be beaten. Besides, there's some good news."

"Oh?"

"Cooper's still in surgery, but prognosis is good, last I heard. And Lyndon made it out just fine; she was here until about an hour or so ago. She left to go to the service."

"The service?"

"The memorial. For the others. Nothing big or official, really. There's no good PR to be had making a big show of this. As far as the public was concerned, this was the biggest policing fiasco of the decade. Heads are going to roll." Travis looked uncomfortable.

Fiona knew what he wasn't saying: so you'd best update your resume.

"We knew that was going to be a possibility—"

There was a knock on the door. Fiona and Travis traded a look.

The door opened.

In walked a man with golden hair and a pearly smile. It was the sort of smile that would get a ping! sound effect in a cartoon to highlight just how shiny it was. He wore an expensive-looking, tailored suit and loafers polished to be almost as bright as his teeth.

He looked a little like Kenneth Branagh, actually.

"Hello," he said pleasantly. "I'm—"

"Gilderoy Lockhart," Fiona said through clenched teeth.

Lockhart smiled happily. "I hadn't realized that my fame had spread quite that far, but, again, why shouldn't it have? Of course even the Muggles know who I am. Then you know why I'm here?"

"I have a pretty good idea," Fiona said. "Cleaning up the last of the loose ends?"

"Precisely," Lockhart smiled again, smoothly drawing a wand. "I'm sure you'll be happy to know that the children are safe. They're going to give me a medal for rescuing them."

Well, that was something, at least. The children were in the hands of their government, not their criminals. A minor victory, if lacking in recognition. Not that, in all likelihood, Fiona was going to remember it.

"How'd you catch us?"

"There's a friendly mediwitch at St Mungo's who told me the other night that a few of Lucius's old friends checked in with some very peculiar injuries. Anyway, I have a little more experience with Muggles than some of my comrades, and it was a simple matter to cross-reference the Muggle-related injuries with the Obliviator's files on certain highly-persistent... ah, what am I saying? Look at me gabbing on, terribly rude. It's not as if you'll remember any of this, anyway. Now, what would you me to replace your memories with?"

"Me kicking Kenneth Branagh posters in their smug faces repeatedly," Fiona spat. "With steel-toed boots."

Lockhart's smile froze briefly. Then he shrugged.

"Oblivio."

o—o—o—o

The official word was that Milo Amastacia-Liadon, an orphan barely in control of his childhood-style accidental wandless magic, had run off from Hogwarts on his own accord. After the massive cleanup operation that the battle with the basilisk necessitated, it was discovered that his bed was made (for the first time since he'd arrived), and all of his possessions had vanished from their drawers.

Similarly, the mysterious person of unknown identity disguised as Seamus Finnigan who had been trapped in the Gryffindor Common Room was also nowhere to be found. The ensuing manhunt led to nothing but dead ends; no-one was able to produce any proof of the identity of the mysterious trapped man. In the end, it was chocked up to general Hogwarts-related-weirdness.

Gilderoy Lockhart received an Order of Merlin, First Class for his daring rescue of the eight missing Hogwarts children, and, after demonstrating his prodigious talents with Memory Charms, was put in charge of the Ministry's Obliviators after their previous leader, Arnold Peasegood, resigned after a stress-induced nervous breakdown. Some questioned why so illustrious a wizard would settle for something as mundane as a government job, or why he resigned from Hogwarts halfway through a school year, but no consistent answer was ever to be had from Lockhart.

Sketches of the missing boy—no photographs, magical or otherwise, could be found of him—were distributed throughout Magical Britain in newspapers and posters. Aside from that, very little effort was made to find him. He existed on no public records, he had no known next of kin, and as a result nobody was quite sure who was responsible for finding him. Everyone simply assumed that, sooner or later, he'd use his magic and the Ministry would detect him in the same way that they caught all other users of unauthorized underaged magic.

Missing. That's what the papers said, and it's what the general public believed.

But it's not what Dumbledore said, and it's not what Hermione believed.

Because they had a piece of evidence that the rest of the wizarding world didn't.

Mordenkainen happily ran in the red plastic wheel of his small rat cage by the window. He'd long since chewed and struggled his way out of the magical apparel Milo had made for him. They couldn't let him out of the cage; he tried to make a run for it, biting anyone who got too close. All evidence suggested he was a completely ordinary, feral rat picked up from the streets somewhere. Even Ron's decrepit rat, Scabbers, seemed more intelligent by comparison.

Hermione remembered that, once before, Milo had tried to explain the concept of a familiar to her. He'd said that, in many ways, a familiar and its master were the same entity, split into two bodies. As the master grew stronger, so did the familiar. If the familiar died, the master was greatly weakened.

But he'd also said that nobody really knew what happened to the familiar when its master died. Nobody had ever cared to find out.

The squeaking of the wheel stopped. Hermione glanced over at Mordy, who was sitting perfectly still, staring through the white bars of his cage and out the window into the Hogwarts grounds. It might have just been her imagination, but it seemed as if he was waiting for someone to come back to him.

o—o—o—o

Lucius Malfoy set down his quill and waited for the ink to dry. He was inches away from having Snape's title—Acting Headmaster—simplified by one inconvenient word. All he needed was to exert a hair more pressure on some of the more moderate members of the Hogwarts Board of Governors.

Once he had the education of the entire future generation of wizards and witches in his hands, all he would need was time. He could subtly shape their thoughts and view of the world, and it would be a simple matter to make certain that some of the new graduates most amenable to the Malfoy way were fast-tracked into middling-to-powerful positions in the Ministry. By the time any of Dumbledore's supporters realized what had happened, it would be too late. That was something that neither Dumbledore nor the late Dark Lord had ever really understood. The Dark Lord always viewed the Ministry as an enemy to be defeated with force and deceit, and Dumbledore never paid it much mind to begin with, turning down a powerful political position in favour being Headmaster. But the system existed, and it pervaded every aspect of ordinary life in Magical Britain. The one who controlled the system controlled everything. Time had already shown Lucius to be victor. The Dark Lord was dead, and Hogwarts was no longer in Dumbledore's hands.

It was only a matter of time.

Lucius neatly folded the parchment, and was just about to stuff it into an envelope when he heard the distinctive popping sound of an Apparating wizard.

He drew his wand beneath his heavy wooden desk, ready to spring into action, if necessary. Outright combat wasn't his preferred way of doing things, but if this mysterious visitor had violence on their minds, they would likely as not never be seen nor heard from again.

The lights flickered out.

"Who's there?" Lucius asked. "Show yourself."

"Why, Lucius," a voice said smoothly. It was a voice like goblin steel cutting silk. Soft, clean, and deadly all at the same time. It was a voice that Lucius Malfoy had hoped to never hear again. "That's no way to greet an old friend, now is it?"

It was the voice of the Dark Lord Voldemort.

o—o—o—o

Fiona awoke in her bed with a strange feeling well-known to anyone who has ever been jolted awake by dream-tripping on the dream-sidewalk. She spent a few seconds taking deep breaths to calm her racing heart.

"Bloody hate those," she muttered to herself, then checked her alarm clock:

6:30.

With an irritated grumble, she rolled over to try and go back to sleep. She'd woken up at 6:30 every day for so long that, now that she no longer had anywhere in particular to be every morning, she couldn't break the habit.

After an unsuccessful ten minutes of trying to fall back to sleep, she rolled out of bed painfully and limped to the kitchen. If being on leave messed with her morning routine, being a cripple destroyed it. It took her more than twice as long to do even basic tasks with her limp as it had.

By the time she'd showered, had breakfast, fed Sprocket, grabbed her vacuum flask full of tea, her walkman, and left, it was already 7:30, which, in her books, was practically afternoon.

Despite being on leave—allegedly for her injury, but really as a reprimand for the fiasco that was the drug bust—she couldn't help but follow her routine. She'd been programmed like a robot. She told herself that she was just walking to the station to get a little fresh air and stretch after being bed-ridden for so long.

She awkwardly put her headphones on, fumbling the unfamiliar cane in one hand and the walkman, tape, and headphones in the other. She eventually had to lean the cane, and herself, against the brick wall of her building to manage it.

Fiona started as, rather than that of Mick Jagger, she heard her own voice through the speakers.

"If you know why you're hearing yourself speak, hold fast-forward for thirty seconds. No? Still here? Damn, they got you again. Well, anyway, here's what's going on..."